Before time began, there was the Cube.
在很久的过去 能量体就已经存在了
We know not where it comes from,
我们不知道它从哪里来
only that it holds the power...
只知道它拥有...
to create worlds and fill them with life.
创造世界和生命的力量
That is how our race was born.
我们这个种族就是这么诞生的
For a time, we lived in harmony,
我们一直和谐地生活着
but like all great power,
就像其它巨大的能量一样
some wanted it for good, others for evil.
人们要它的目的有善有恶
And so began the war,
所以战争开始了
a war that ravaged our planet...
一场使我们的星球...
until it was consumed by death,
毁灭的战争
and the Cube was lost to the far reaches of space.
能量体也丢失在浩瀚的宇宙里
We scattered across the galaxy,
我们搜寻了整个银河
hoping to find it and rebuild our home,
希望可以找到它来重建我们的家园
searching every star, every world.
寻找每一个星球 每一个世界
And just when all hope seemed lost,
就当我们都失去希望时
message of a new discovery...
新的线索...
drew us to an unknown planet called
把我们带到了一个星球叫做...
Earth.
地球
But we were already too late.
但是我们已经太迟了
Oh, God, five months of this.
上帝啊 都已经5个月了
I can't wait to get a little taste of home
我都等不及要回家了
A plate of mama's alligators touffe.
我很想念我妈妈煮的鳄鱼肉
You've been talking about barbecued 'gators...
你说这些鳄鱼肉...
and crickets for the last two weeks.
都说了2个星期了
I'm never going to your mama's house, I promise.
我发誓我一定不会去你妈妈那里吃饭
But Bobby, Bobby, 'gators are...
博比 鳄鱼肉是...
known to have the most succulent meat.
出了名的嫩
I understand
我理解
English, please. English.
请说英语好吗?
I mean, how many times have we...
我说过多少次了...
We don't speak Spanish. I told you that.
我们不讲西班牙语 我告诉过你的
Why you got to ruin it for me, man?
你们干嘛总要破坏...
That's my heritage.
我自己的传统呢?
Go with the Spanish. Whatever
你随便说吧
Hey, you guys remember weekends? Huh?
你们还记得我们是怎么过周末的吗?
The Sox at Fenway.
在芬维公园看红袜队的比赛
- Cold hotdog and a flat beer. - Perfect day
- 美味的热狗和冰镇的啤酒 - 完美的一天
What about you, Captain? You got a perfect day?
你呢 队长? 你也有完美的一天吗?
I just can't wait to hold...
我已经等不及去...
my baby girl for the first time.
第一次抱我的女儿
- He's adorable. - That's too...
- 好男人啊 - 太...
Shut up!
闭嘴!
Hey, I'm ready to do this.
我都准备好了
Hey, any of y'all grow some balls,
你们谁有胆量
come see me on the court, man.
就来操场上见我
Hey, hey!
嘿!
Watch this crossover, baby.
小心我的胯下运球
Like Jordan in his prime,
就像乔丹全盛时期一样
pushing through the front line.
穿梭于锋线间
- Step aside, ladies. - Oh, man. What?
- 让开点 小妞们 - 什么?
- Lennox! - Hey, what are you doing?
- 兰诺斯! - 你好啊
- Water? - Thank you
- 要水吗? - 谢谢
Are you gonna help me with the gear?
你要帮我拿装备吗?
Colonel Sharp, we have an inbound unidentified...
夏普上校 有一身份不明的...
infiltrator, 10 miles out.
入侵者 距离10英里
Unidentified aircraft,
不明身份的飞机
you are in restricted US military airspace.
你现位于美军管制空域
Squawk ident and proceed east out of the area.
请表明身份并 向东飞行离开美军的领空
Raptors one and two,
猛禽1号 2号
snap to heading two-five-zero to intercept.
目标方向250 进行拦截
Bogie is in the weeds ten miles out, not squawking.
目标距离10英里 没表明身份
Unidentified aircraft,
不明身份的飞机
we will escort you to US SOCCENT airbase.
我们会护送你到美军桑克森空军基地
If you do not comply, we will use deadly force.
如果你不遵从 我们会使用致命的武力
Copy the bogie
发现目标
Tail 4500 X-ray.
机尾编号4500X
Sir,says here 4500 X was shot down three months ago.
长官 报告说4500X 在3个月前被击落了
- Afghanistan. - That's got to be a mistake
- 在阿富汗 - 这一定是一个错误
- Check again, then recheck. - I did, sir.
- 检查 再检查 - 我检查过了 长官
A friend of mine was on that chopper.
我有一个朋友就在那架直升机上
Unidentified aircraft,
不明身份的飞机
we will escort you to US SOCCENT airbase.
我们会护送你到桑克森空军基地
Radar, where's the inbound?
雷达 飞行物在哪?
Bogie's five miles out, sir.
目标5英里 长官
- My wife on? - Yes, Captain.
- 是我老婆吗? - 是的 队长
- My ladies! - Look.
- 我的公主! - 看
Oh, my goodness. Look at her. She's getting so big.
哦 看啊 她都这么大了
Look at those cheeks. I just wanna chew on them.
看看她的小脸 真想去亲一口
Baby, we made a good-looking kid.
我们的孩子真是漂亮
I know that people say that all the time,
我知道人们总是这么说
but, wow, we made one good-Iooking kid. Nice work.
我们生了一个漂亮的孩子 干得好
She has your laugh
她笑得真像你
- She laughed? - Her first one, yeah.
- 她笑了? - 第一次呢
You sure she didn't just fart?
你确定她刚刚没有放屁吗?
No, she's a lady.
没有 她可是一个淑女
She doesn't know you yet, but she will.
她还不认识你 但是她会的
4500 X. Something's not right
4500X 好像有些不对劲
Bogie's on the deck.
目标着落了
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Radar's jammed.
雷达被干扰了
It's coming from the chopper
直升机是干扰源
- Will? - Sarah?
- 威尔? - 萨拉?
Hey, Sarah, if you can hear me,
莎拉 如果你能听见我
I love you and I'll be home soon.
我爱你 我很快就会回家
- To the right. Go to the right. - Check fire
- 到右边去 到右边去 - 检查弹药
MH-53 pilot, power down now.
MH-53飞行员 关闭你的发动机
Have your crew step out or we will kill you.
让你的机组人员下机 不然我们会杀了你们
Hold your fire! Stand by to engage!
不要开火! 待命!
My God
上帝啊
They bombed the antenna farm! We're under attack!
他们炸了通讯天线 我们被攻击了
Go! Move! Move!
快走! 快!
It's going after the files!
它们想要的是这些机密文件!
Cut the hard lines!
切断总电源!
I need a key! It's locked!
我要钥匙 它被锁上了!
Move! Move!
快走!
Here, come here! Come here!
到这边! 到这边!
Here, hide in here!
藏在这!
Oh, my God. Okay.
哦 上帝啊
No!
不!
Oh!
哦!
What the...
怎么...
Epps, let's go!
埃普斯 快走!
Okay, Mr. Witwicky, you're up.
维特维奇先生 该你了
Sorry, I got a lot of stuff.
对不起 我带了很多东西
Watch
瞧吧
Okay
好的
For my family...
对于我们家族...
Who did... Who did that? People! Responsibility
是谁干的? 谁干的? 同学们 要有责任感
Okay
好吧
So, for my family genealogy report,
对于家族史这个报告
I decided to do it on my great-great-grandfather,
我打算讲我的曾曾祖父
who was a famous man, Captain Archibald Witwicky.
他是一个著名的人 阿奇伯尔德·维特维奇船长
Very famous explorer
著名的探索家
In fact, he was one of the first to explore...
实际上 他是第一个去探索...
the Arctic Circle, which is a big deal.
北极的人 那是一件非常困难的事
In 1897,
在1897年
he took 41 brave sailors straight...
他带着41个勇敢的水手...
into the Arctic Shelf.
向北极出发
Move faster, men! Move! Chop! Heave!
大家加把劲! 敲! 举起来!
The ice is freezing faster than it's melting!
冰结的比它化的还要快!
Chop faster! Heave, men!
大家再加把劲!
- Heave! - No sacrifice, no victory!
- 举起来! - 没有付出 就没有胜利
We'll get to the Arctic Circle, lads!
我们会到达那里的 伙计们!
So that's the story, right?
这就是我要讲的故事
And here we have some of the basic instruments...
这里 我有一些基本资料
and tools used by 19th-century seamen
和工具 是19世纪水手所用的
This here is the quadrant,
这是四分仪
which you can get for 80 bucks.
只要80美元就可以给你
It's all for sale, by the way.
这些都是要卖的
Like the sextant here.
这个六分仪
$50 for this, which is a bargain.
50美元 非常超值
These are pretty cool.
这个最酷了
These are my grandfather's glasses.
它是我曾曾祖父的眼镜
I haven't quite gotten them appraised yet,
我还没给它估价
but they've seen many cool things.
它见过很多有趣的事
Are you going to sell me his liver?
你要卖我他的肝吗?
Mr. Witwicky,
维特维奇先生
this isn't show and sell. It's the 11th grade.
这不是跳蚤市场 这是11年级的课堂
I don't think your grandfather would be
我想你的祖父不会
particularly proud of what you're doing
为你所作所为感到骄傲的
I know. I'm sorry. I just, you know,
我知道 对不起 这只是...
this is all going towards my car fund.
都是为了我的汽车基金
You can tell your folks. It's on eBay. I take PayPal
你可以告诉其他人 我在易趣卖
Cold hard cash works, too.
接受贝宝和现金
And the compass makes a great gift for Columbus Day
指南针是一个很好的哥伦布节的礼物
- Sam! - Sorry
- 山姆 - 对不起
Unfortunately, my great-great-grandfather,
不幸的是 我的曾曾祖父
the genius that he was,
虽然是个天才
wound up going blind and crazy in a psycho ward,
却瞎了又疯了 被关进精神病院
drawing these strange symbols
画这些奇怪的符号
and babbling on about some giant ice man
说一些关于他所发现的
that he thought he'd discovered
巨大的冰人的事情
Okay. Might be a pop quiz tomorrow. Might not
也许明天会有考试 也许不会
Sleep in fear tonight.
今晚在恐惧中入睡吧
Here, you want? Here, 50. 40? 30?
要吗? 50 40 30?
- Sam? - Yeah. Sorry, sorry.
- 山姆 - 对不起 对不起
Okay. Pretty good, right?
很不错 对吗?
I'd say a solid B- .
我想B-是一个不错的成绩
You were hawking your great-grandfather's crap
你在说一些关于你曾曾祖父的无聊的事情
- in my classroom. - No, kids enjoy...
- 在我的课堂上 - 不 大家喜欢...
- Look, can you do me a favor? - What?
- 能帮个忙吗? - 干什么?
Can you look out the window for a second?
你能看一下窗外吗?
You see my father?
看到我父亲了吗?
- He's the guy in the green car. - Yeah
- 坐在绿色的车里 - 嗯
Okay, I wanna tell you about a dream. A boy's dream.
我要告诉你一个梦想 一个男孩的梦想
And a man's promise to that boy
一个男人答应那个男孩
He looked at me in the eye. He said,
他看着我的眼睛说
"Son, I'm gonna buy you a car.
儿子 我会给你买一辆车
"But I want you to bring me $2,000 and three As."
但是你需要给我2000美元和3个A
Okay? I got the 2,000 and I got two As.
我已经有了2000美元和2个A
Okay? Here's the dream. Your B- . Dream gone. Kaput.
这是我的梦想 你的B- 梦想破灭了
Sir, just ask yourself, what would Jesus do?
先生 你自问一下 如果是上帝 他会怎么做?
Yes! Yes, yes.
太棒了!
So?
怎么样?
A- . It's an A, though.
A- 但也算A
Wait, wait, wait. I can't see. It's an A.
等一等 我看不清楚 是A 没问题
- So I'm good? - You're good
- 那么 通过啦? - 通过啦
I got a little surprise for you, son.
儿子 我有一个惊喜给你
What kind of...
什么样的惊喜?
Yeah, a little surprise.
小小的惊喜
No. No, no, no, no. Dad!
不 不 不 不 爸爸!
- Oh, you got to be kidding me. - See?
- 你一定是在开玩笑 - 看?
Yeah. I am. You're not getting a Porsche
是的 我是在开玩笑 你不会得到一辆保时捷
You think that's funny?
你认为那很可笑吗?
Yeah, I think it's funny.
是的 非常可笑
- What's wrong with you? - You think I'd really
- 你怎么回事? - 你真以为...
get you a Porsche for your first car?
我给你买的第一辆车就是保时捷?
I don't want to talk to you...
我以后不会再...
for the rest of this whole thing
和你谈这件事了
Oh, come on. It's just a practical joke.
哦 拜托 就是个现实的玩笑
It's not a funny joke.
一点不好笑
- Manny! - What?
- 曼尼! - 怎么?
Get your cousin out of that damn clown suit
别让你表弟穿这个
He's having a heat stroke again
他热得发晕了
Scaring white folks
吓坏了白人客户
I'm hot! Makeup's melting. It hurts my eyes
我很热! 妆要化了 我眼睛疼
Here? No, no, no, what is this?
这? 不! 这是什么?
You said... You said half a car,
你...你说过半辆车
not half a piece of crap, Dad.
不是半辆破烂 爸爸
When I was your age,
我像你这么大时
I'd have been happy with four wheels and an engine.
能有辆车就很开心了
Okay, let me explain something to you. Okay?
让我来解释解释 好吗?
- You ever see 40-Year-Old Virgin? - Yeah.
- 看没看过《40岁的处男》? - 看过
Okay, that's what this is.
这就是他
And this is 50-year-old virgin.
这是50岁的处男
- Okay. - You want me to live that life?
- 好吧 - 你想我以后变成这样吗?
No sacrifice, no victory.
没有付出 就没有胜利
Yeah, no victory. You know, I got it.
嗯 没有胜利 我知道
- The old Witwicky motto, Dad. - Right.
- 我知道这句维奇家的格言 - 对
Gentlemen
先生们
Bobby Bolivia,
鲍比·玻利维亚
like the country, except without the runs.
就像那个国家 除了不是逃来的
How can I help you?
想要点什么?
Well, my son here, looking to buy his first car.
我儿子要买他的第一辆车
- You come to see me? - I had to
- 所以你来找我了? - 没办法
That practically makes us family.
那我们就是一家人了
Uncle Bobby B, baby. Uncle Bobby B.
你可以叫我鲍比·B叔叔
- Sam. - Sam, let me talk to you.
- 山姆 - 山姆 我来跟你说
Sam, your first enchilada of freedom...
山姆 你的第一道大餐...
awaits underneath one of those hoods.
就在那里面
Let me tell you something, son.
我来告诉你
A driver don't pick the car.
不是驾驶员挑车
The car'll pick the driver
而是车挑驾驶员
It's a mystical bond between man and machine
这是人类和汽车间的缘分
Son, I'm a lot of things,
孩子 我本事很大的
but a liar's not one of them.
但不包括吹牛
Especially not in front of my mammy.
尤其不在我妈妈面前
That's my mammy. Hey, Mammy!
那就是我妈妈 嘿 妈咪!
Don't be like that.
别那样
If I had a rock, I'd bust your head, bitch.
我要是有块石头 就砸你的头 婊子
I tell you, man, she deaf, you know?
我告诉你 伙计 她聋了
Well, over here,
看这边
every piece of car a man might want or need.
每辆都不错 都是你所想要的
This ain't bad
这辆不错
- This one's got racing stripes. - Yeah
- 这车有赛车的条纹 - 是啊
It got racing...
有条纹...
Yeah, what's this? What the heck is this?
这到底是哪辆?
I don't know nothing about this car
我不知道这辆车
- Manny! - What?
- 曼尼! - 干什么?
What is this? This car! Check it out!
这是谁的车? 去查一下!
I don't know, boss! I've never seen it! That's loco!
我不知道 老板 我以前没见过!
Don't go Ricky Ricardo on me, Manny! Find out!
别唬我 快去查查!
Feels good
感觉不错
- How much? - Well,
- 多少钱 - 嗯
considering the semi-classic nature of the vehicle,
根据这辆车的外形
with the slick wheels and the custom paint job...
和特别的喷漆
Yeah, but the paint's faded.
漆已经掉色了
Yeah, but it's custom.
是的 但是喷漆是特殊的
It's custom faded?
那是特殊的掉色漆吗?
Well, this is your first car.
这是你第一辆车
I wouldn't expect you to understand.
我不指望你明白
Five grand.
5千
No, I'm not paying over four. Sorry.
抱歉 不会超过4千
Kid, come on, get out. Get out the car.
孩子 从车里出来
No, no, no. You said cars pick their drivers.
不 不 不 但是你说车挑驾驶员
Well, sometimes they pick a driver...
但是 有时那个驾驶员...
with a cheap-ass father. Out the car.
有一个抠门的父亲 快下车
Now, this one here for four Gs is a beaut.
这边这辆就4千美元了
There's a Fiesta with racing stripes over there
那车也有赛车的条纹
No, I don't want a Fiesta with racing stripes.
我不想要那个带条纹的福特嘉年华
This is a classic engine right here
这车有一个经典的引擎
I sold a car the other day...
前几天卖一辆
Gee. Holy cow
哦 天啊
- No, no, no. No worries. - You all right?
- 别担心 - 你没事吧?
I'll get a sledgehammer and knock this right out.
我去弄个大锤把这个敲下来
Hey, hey, Manny!
嘿 曼尼!
Get your clown cousin and get some hammers
让你表弟弄些锤子来
and come bang this stuff out, baby!
把这东西敲下去
... greater than man...
...比人类伟大...
That one's my favorite,
那辆我最喜欢
drove all the way from Alabammy.
一路从阿拉巴马开过来
$4,000.
4千
Steve
史蒂文
Hello, Mr. Secretary.
你好 部长先生
They're so young
他们太年轻了
They're the top subject matter experts, sir.
他们是最好的主题专家
NSA's recruiting right out of high school these days
这些年国家安全局直接从高中招人
Guys, that's the Secretary of Defense.
同伴们 那是国防部部长
I am so underdressed
我穿的衣服真不适合这个场合
Ladies and gentlemen, the Secretary of Defense.
女士们 先生们 国防部部长
Please be seated
请坐
I'm John Keller
我是约翰·凯勒
Obviously, you're wondering why you're here,
你们应该想知道你们为什么会在这里
so these are the facts.
事实上是这样的
At 1900 local time yesterday,
在昨天当地时间19时
the SOCCENT Forward Operations...
在卡塔尔的桑克森
Base in Qatar was attacked.
美军基地被攻击了
So far as we know, there were no survivors.
具目前所了解的资料 没有幸存者
The objective of the attack...
攻击的目的是为了...
was to hack our military network
侵入军方的电脑网络
We're not sure exactly what they're after,
我们并不知道他们要找什么
but we do know...
但是我们知道...
that they were cut off during the assault,
他们的侵入被阻止了
which would lead us to assume...
所以我们认为...
that they're going to try it again
他们会再次袭击
Now, no one's taken responsibility for the attack.
目前无人为攻击事件负责
And the only real lead we have so far...
我们现在唯一的线索...
is this sound.
是这个声音
That's the signal that hacked our network
那是侵入我们系统的信号
NSA's working at full capacity to analyze it
国家安全局正在全力分析它
and intercept further communications,
希望来拦截未来的通讯
but we need your help to find out who did this
我们需要你来找出谁是幕后的主脑
Now, you've all shown considerable ability...
你们都有很强的...
in the area of signals analysis.
信号分析技能
We're on a hair-trigger here, people.
现在情况紧急
The President has dispatched battle groups
总统已经派出航母战斗群
to the Arabian Gulf and Yellow Sea.
前往波斯湾和黄海
This is as real as it's ever gonna get.
再也不会比这更严重了
Now I'm gonna leave you to your officer-in-charge.
你们会由负责的官员领导
You'll break up into teams...
领队们会把你们分成小组...
and you'll start your work
开始工作
Good luck to us all
祝我们好运
All right, Mojo. I got the car. Now I need the girl.
好了 魔咒 我有车了 我需要一个女朋友
I need money to take out the girl is what I need
我还需要钱带她出去玩
Zero bids
0个竞标
Great. Broke
真是太好了 身无分文
Come on, Mojo. You want your pain pills?
魔咒 你想要你的止痛药吗?
No. Premature
还没熟透
Good. What's up?
你好吗?
Nothing. You know, just driving my car.
没什么 只是在开我的车
Driving my car.
开我的车
It's like clockwork
就像是时钟发条
All right, I know you get wasted on these things,
我知道这东西让你恍惚了
but if you piss in my bed again,
但你要是再在我床上撒尿
you're sleeping outside. Okay?
就到外面睡去 明白?
That's it for today. No more. Crackhead
今天到此为止了 别吃了 瘾君子
- Ron, this one is uneven. - Yeah. Probably.
- 荣恩 这里不平 - 也许吧
This one is wobbly
这块要掉了
Yeah. I'll take care of that real soon.
是的 我会解决它的
Couldn't we have hired a professional?
我们能不能请一个专业的人?
- Sam... - What?
- 山姆... - 干什么?
I do not like footprints on my grass
我不想在我的草坪上看到脚印
What foot... There's no footprints.
什么...? 没脚印啊
That's why I built my path
这就是我为什么修了入门径
So why don't you go from my grass onto my path,okay?
你为什么不从草地移到入门径上来?
It's family grass, Dad.
这草是属于整个家的
Well, when you own your own grass,
当你拥有你自己的草地的时候
you'll understand.
你会明白的
This... I can't do it anymore
这...我受不了了
You're putting girl jewelry on a boy dog.
你把女性的饰品戴在一条雄性的狗身上
He's got enough self-esteem...
作为一条吉娃娃犬
issues as a Chihuahua, Mom.
他有严重的自信心问题
That's his bling
那是他的首饰
I want you home at 11:00!
在11点前回家!
- Yeah, all right. - 11:00!
- 没问题 - 11点
Please, for the love of God, drive safely.
看在上帝的份上 小心开车
Seat belt on!
系上安全带!
Wow. You are so cheap
喔 你可真小气
Well, it's his first car. Supposed to be like that.
那是他的第一辆车 应该是这样的
At this time, we can't confirm...
目前 我们无法确认
whether there were any survivors.
是否有幸存者存在
Oh, my God.
天啊
Our bases worldwide are, as of now, at DEFCON Delta,
我们现在进入防御状况四
our highest readiness level.
这是最高警戒
We're dealing with a very effective weapons system
我们面对着一个从未见过的
that we have not come across before
非常强大的武器系统
But our prayers are with the families of the...
我们会为那些勇敢的士兵祈祷
Honey, Daddy's gonna be okay.
爸爸会没事的
I've never seen a weapons system like this
我以前从未见过这种武器系统
The thermal shows this...
热成像显示...
weird aura around the exoskeleton like it's...
在它的外骨骼结构周围...
cloaked by some kind of invisible force field.
有一个无形的能量罩
That's impossible.
那不可能
There's no such thing as invisible force fields
根本没有无形的能量罩
except in, like, comic book stuff, right?
除了在漫画里 对吗?
- Man, I don't know. - What is that?
- 我不明白 - 怎么了?
My mama, she had the gift, you know?
我老妈 她有种天赋
She saw things. I got the gene, too,
我妈妈可以看到未来 我也有她的遗传
and that thing that attacked us?
那个攻击我们的家伙
I got a feeling it ain't over.
我预感它还会再来
How about you use those magic voodoo powers
你为什么不用你的巫术
and get us the hell out of here, huh?
让我们离开这里
When I took that picture, I think it saw me.
当我照相的时候 我想它看到我了
It looked right at me.
它盯着我看
All right, we got to get this thing...
我们要马上把它...
back to the Pentagon right away.
送到五角大楼
They got to know what we're dealing with here
他们要知道我们的敌人是什么
My radio's fried.
无线电失灵了
I got no communication with aerial.
天线没有信号
Hey, Mahfouz.
马弗斯
How far do you live from here?
你家离这里有多远?
Not far. Just up that mountain.
不远了 翻过那座山就到了
- Do they have a phone? - Yes
- 那里有电话吗? - 是的
All right, let's hit it.
好的 我们走
Dude, are you sure we're invited to this party?
你确定我们被邀请去这个聚会了吗?
Of course, Miles. It's a lake. Public property.
当然了 迈尔斯 那是一个湖 是公共场所
Oh, my God.
我的天啊
Oh, my God, dude, Mikaela's here.
我的天啊 梅卡拉在这
Just don't do anything weird, all right?
别做奇怪的事 好吧?
- I'm good, right? - Yeah, you're good.
- 我看上不错 对不对? - 是的
Okay
好的
Hey, guys, check it out.
快看
Oh, hi.
嘿
Hey, bro. That car. It's nice. Hey.
嘿 你的车不错
So, what are you guys doing here?
你们来这里干什么?
We're here to climb this tree.
我们来这里爬这棵树
I see that. It looks... It looks fun.
看见了 很有趣
- Yeah. - You know, I thought I recognized you.
- 嗯 - 我想我认识你
You tried out for the football team last year,right?
你去年参加过橄榄球队的预选 对吧
Let's go call your mom
我们去找你的妈妈.
Oh, no, no, that... No.
不 不 那是... 不是
That wasn't like a real tryout.
我并不是想参加预选
I was researching a book I was writing.
我是在为写的书收集资料
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
- 是吗? - 是的
Yeah? What's it about? Sucking at sports?
关于什么的? 一塌糊涂的体育运动?
No, it's about the link...
不 那是关于...
between brain damage and football.
橄榄球和大脑受损的
No, it's a good book. Your friends'll love it.
那是一本好书 你的朋友会喜欢它的
You know, it's got mazes in it and,
有上色的地方
you know, little coloring areas,
立体折叠...
sections, pop-up pictures. It's a lot of fun.
...还有图片 非常有趣
That's funny.
真是好笑
Okay, okay. You know what? Stop.
不要这样
Hey, guys, I know of a party. Let's go, let's head.
我们去参加聚会吧
You got to get out of the tree right now. Get...
快从树上下来...
Just get out of the tree right now, please.
快下来 拜托
What are you doing?
你在干什么?
Did you see that dismount?
看到下来的动作了?
All the chicks were watching.
女孩们都在看我
You're making me look like an idiot.
你使我看起来像个傻瓜
We both looked like idiots just now.
我们刚才都像傻瓜
Hey, how about you let me drive?
嘿 让我开怎么样?
Oh, no. No, no, no. This is not a toy.
这可不行 这可不是一个玩具车
These 22s, I don't want you grinding them. No.
这个22英寸的轮胎 我不想你开
Why doesn't my little bunny...
为什么我可爱的小白兔...
just hop in the back seat?
不跳到后座上去?
God, I can't even tell you how much...
噢 天 我要告诉你
I'm not your little bunny.
我可不是你的小白兔
Okay.
好吧
You'll call me.
你会来找我的
Who's gonna drive you home, tonight?
∮ 今晚谁开车送你回家? ∮
Hey, man, what's wrong with your radio?
你的收音机怎么了?
- I'm gonna drive her home tonight. - What?
- 今晚我要送她回家 - 什么?
She's an evil jock concubine, man.
她可是个小骚货 伙计
Let her hitchhike.
让她去搭车吧
She lives 10 miles from here, okay?
她家离这里有10英里远
It's my only chance.
这是我唯一的机会
You got to be understanding here, all right?
你要理解我 好吗?
All right. We'll put her in the back. I'll be quiet.
把她放在后座 我会安静的
Did you say, "Put her in the back"?
你是不是说 "让她坐在后座"?
I called shotgun.
我说坐前面
I'm not putting her in the back.
我不会让她坐后面
You got to get out of my car.
你得下车
- That's a party foul. - What rules?
- 这可违反了聚会规则 - 什么规则?
Bros before hos.
不能重色轻友
Miles, I'm begging you to get out of my car. Okay?
迈尔斯 我求你下车
You can't do this to me.
你不能这样对我
You got to get out of my car right now.
你必须下车
Who's gonna come around when you break?
∮ 你受伤时谁陪在你身边? ∮
Mikaela! It's Sam.
梅卡拉 我是山姆
Witwicky.
维特维奇
I hope I didn't get you stranded or anything.
希望没有让你感到进退两难
You sure?
是吧?
So listen, I was wondering if I could ride you home.
我可不可以载你回家?
I mean give you a ride home in my car to your house.
我是说我开车送你回家
There you go.
上车吧
So...
那么...
I can't believe that I'm here right now.
我真不敢相信我现在坐在这里
You can duck down if you want.
愿意的话你可以把头低下
I mean, it won't hurt my feelings.
我不会感到难过的
Oh, no, no, no. I didn't mean here with you.
我不是说和你在一块
I just meant here, like, in this situation,
我是说现在这种状况
this same situation that I'm always in.
我总是把自己至于这种境地
'Cause, I don't know,
我不知道为什么
I guess I just have a weakness for hot guys,
我想 我是对肌肉男有特殊的喜好
for tight abs and really big arms
那种紧紧的肌肉 结实的臂膀
Big arms?
结实的臂膀?
Well, there's a couple new additions in the car.
这车上有几种新物件
Like, I just put in that light there.
我刚刚装了那个灯
And that disco ball.
还有这个迪斯可球
And so the light reflects off the disco ball.
用那盏灯照这个迪斯可球
Yeah.
没错
Are you new to school this year?
你是刚刚到这个学校的吗?
It's your first year here?
这是你第一年在这里上学吗?
Oh, no, no.
不 不
We've been in the same school since first grade.
我们从一年级开始就在同一所学校
- Really? - Yeah.
- 真的? - 没错
Yeah, a long time.
真的是很久了
Well, do we have any classes together?
我们有同堂的课吗?
- Yeah, yeah. - Really? Which?
- 有的 - 真的? 什么课?
History. Language arts. Math. Science.
历史 语言 数学 科学
- Sam. - Sam. Yeah.
- 你叫山姆 - 山姆 没错
- Sam Wilkicky. - Witwicky.
- 山姆·维特齐齐 - 维特维奇
God, you know what? I'm so sorry. I just...
我真是很对不起
- No, it's cool. - I just didn't recognize you.
- 没关系 - 我没认出你来
Yeah, well, I mean, that's understandable.
没什么 可以理解
No, no, no. No. Come on.
不 不要 拜托
Sorry, I'm just working out the kinks.
抱歉 我才刚刚修过
You know, it's a new car.
这是辆新车
When I get that feeling I want sexual healing.
∮ 当欲望来时 性爱疗法是我所需 ∮
This radio is, like, you know...
这收音机...你知道...
It's an old radio, too, so...
也是个旧的 所以...
Sexual healing.
∮ 性爱疗法 ∮
Look, this isn't something that I, you know...
我也不知道为什么
I can't get this radio to stop.
我没法关掉收音机
Look, I wouldn't try this on you.
我不是故意的
'Cause this is like a romantic thing...
这有点罗曼蒂克
that I'm not trying to do.
我不想这样的
Not that you're not worthy of...
不应该对你...
trying something like this on
这样做的
- No, of course not. - I'm a friend of yours.
- 当然 - 我是你的朋友
I'm not a romantic friend. Romantic friends do this.
不是个罗曼蒂克的朋友 罗曼蒂克的朋友才这样
I mean, I'm not that friend.
我是说 我不是那种朋友
I mean, we... I could be.
我是说 我们...我可以是的
I feel good.
∮ 我感觉不错 ∮
Just pop the hood.
打开引擎罩
Stupid. Shut up, shut up, shut up.
白痴! 闭嘴 闭嘴!
Whoa, nice headers.
缸头真不错
You've got a high-rise double-pump carburetor.
高置双泵渗碳缸头
That's pretty impressive, Sam.
印象深刻 山姆
Double-pump?
双泵?
It squirts the fuel in so you can go faster.
汽油进的更快 你可以开的更快
I like to go faster.
我喜欢开快一些
And it looks like your...
看起来你的...
distributor cap's a little loose.
配电盘封盖有些松了
Yeah? How'd you know that?
是吗? 你是怎么知道的?
My dad. He was a real grease monkey.
我爸爸 他是汽车机械师
He taught me all about this.
他教会我这些的
I could take it all apart,
我可以把它拆了
clean it, put it back together.
清洗一下 再装起来
That's weird.I just wouldn't peg you for mechanical.
真奇怪 我一定不会花钱请你当修车工
Oh, my God.
噢 上帝啊
Well, you know, I don't really broadcast it.
我不声张
Guys don't like it when...
男人不喜欢...
you know more about cars than they do.
女人比他们更懂车
Especially not Trent. He hates it.
特别是崔恩 他讨厌这些
Yeah, no, I'm cool with, you know,
不 我并不介意
females working on my engine.
女人来修引擎
I prefer it, actually.
实际上 我挺喜欢
Okay. You want to fire it up for me?
你想试一下点火吗?
Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.
噢 对 没问题
- Thanks. - You know, I was thinking.
- 谢谢 - 我在想
You know, if Trent's such a jerk,
如果崔恩是个混蛋
why do you hang out with him?
你为什么还和他在一起
You know what? I'm just... I'm gonna walk.
嗯...我要走路回去了
Good luck with your car.
祝你的车好运
All right.
好吧
Walking's healthy, right?
走路有益健康 是吧
Oh, God, no, no, no, no, no, no.
哦 上帝 不 不 不
Come on, please. Please, you gotta work for me now.
拜托 快好起来吧
Don't let her walk away.
不要让她走掉
Come on, come on, come on. Please, please.
拜托 求求你
Baby come back any kind of fool could see.
∮ 宝贝回来吧 傻瓜都看得出来 ∮
Hey!
嘿!
There was something in everything about you.
∮ 都是为了你 ∮
Baby come back you can blame it all on me.
∮ 宝贝回来吧 你可以怪我的 ∮
Hey!
嘿!
Wait a second!
等一下!
I was wrong and I just can't live without you.
∮ 我错了 我不能没有你 ∮
There it is.
到了
I had fun. So, you know, thanks for listening.
我今天很高兴 感谢你听我发牢骚
Oh, yeah, yeah.
噢 嗯
You... You think I'm shallow?
你...你是不是认为我很肤浅?
I think you're... No, no, no.
我觉得你...不 不 不
I think...
我觉得
there's a lot more than meets the eye with you.
你并非徒有其表
Okay.
好的
Yeah.
嗯
All right, I'll see you at school.
学校见
All right.
好的
That's stupid.
真傻
That was a stupid line.
真傻的台词
"There's more than meets the eye with you." Stupid.
"你并非徒有其表" 真傻
Oh, God.
哦 上帝
Oh, my God. I love my car.
哦 上帝 我喜欢这车
Hey, guys, I think the other team figured it out.
嘿 伙计们 我想另一个小组找出原因了
Iran.
伊朗人
Come on, man.
拜托 伙计
This is way too smart for Iranian scientists.
这对伊朗科学家也太难了点
Think about it.
想想吧
What do you think, kid? Chinese?
你觉得呢? 中国人?
No way.
不可能
This is nothing like what the Chinese are using.
这和中国所用的技术一点也不像
This is Air Force One.
这里是空军一号
Level of flight, level three-three-zero.
飞行高度330
We will hunt down this enemy. And when we do,
我们要找到这个敌人
we'll know just what to do with them.
那时就能知道怎样对付他们
- Thank you. - You're welcome
- 谢谢 - 不客气
Apparently, there are very few survivors.
很明显 幸存者很少
Yes, Mr. President?
总统先生?
Yeah, can you wrangle me up some Ding Dongs,darling?
给我拿一点点心来好吗 亲爱的?
I joined the Air Force to bring the man Ding Dongs.
我加入空军一号就是给他拿点心的
I'll be in storage.
我去储藏室
Shoot.
该死的
Gross.
真恶心
Do you hear that?
你们听到了吗?
I think they're hacking the network again.
我想他们又在入侵军事网络了
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
This is a direct match to the signal in Qatar.
这个和卡塔尔的信号完全一致
- Are you running a diagnostic? - Should I be?
- 你在进行信号分析吗? - 应该吗?
- Yes, you should. - So I am.
- 应该 - 我这就办
Someone! They're hacking into Air Force One!
来人! 它们正入侵空军一号的网络!
We need a senior analyst.
我们需要一个高级分析师
- I think they're planting a virus. - A virus?
- 我想它们植入了一个病毒 - 病毒?
It's streaming right now.
正在传输
They are planting a virus.
他们在植入病毒
and stealing a whole lot of data...
同时还从我们系统上...
from your system at the same time.
窃取了大量的信息
Code Red. We have a breach.
红色警报 网络被入侵了
Air Force One,
空军一号
someone onboard has breached the military network.
有人正在入侵军事网络
I'm in the cargo hold. Clear. Clear
货舱没有人
- You got to cut the hard lines. - What?
- 你们必须切断热线 - 什么?
- Whatever they want, they are getting it. - Sir?
- 不管它们想要什么 它们正在得逞 - 长官?
Permission to take down the Defense Network.
请求切断防御网络
Cut all server hard lines now.
切断所有服务器的连接
Someone's tampered with the POTUS mainframe.
有人动过这里的主机
What the...
怎么...
Shots fired in the underdeck. Repeat, shots fired.
底舱有人开枪 重复 有人开枪
Crew, prepare for emergency descent.
机组 准备紧急降落
I want our President in that bunker.
我要总统现在就进入地下掩体
And I don't want to discuss a damn thing other
我要在他安全后
till that becomes reality.
再讨论现在这个问题
That's our first priority.
这是我们的首要目标
That's our only priority right now.
也是我们现在的唯一目标
Air Force One is on the ground.
空军一号已经降落了
Oh, God. No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
哦 上帝 不 不 不!
That's my car!
那是我的车!
No!
不!
No, no, no, no.
不 不 不
Dad, call the cops!
爸爸 报警
Where you going with my car,buddy? Where you going?
你要开我的车去哪?
Hello? 911 emergency! My car has been stolen!
我要报警 我的车被偷了!
I'm in pursuit! Right?
我正在追他
I need all units, the whole squadron.
所有单位和中队都要行动!
Bring everyone!
把所有人都叫来!
No, don't ask me questions, all right?
不! 别问我问题 行吗?
My father's the head of the neighborhood watch!
我爸爸是邻居保安计划主管!
Oh, my God.
哦 上帝
My name is Sam Witwicky.
我叫山姆·维特维奇
Whoever finds this, my car is alive, okay?
不论谁看到这个 我的车活了
You saw that?
看到了?
Since this is my last words on Earth,
这是我的遗言
I just wanna say, Mom, Dad, I love you,
我爱你爸爸 妈妈
and if you find Busty Beauties under my bed,
如果你们从床下找到色情书刊
it wasn't mine.
那不是我的
I'm holding it for Miles. No, no, wait that...
我是替迈尔斯在保存 不 等等...
Okay, that's not true.
不 那不是真的
It's mine and Uncle Charles gave it to me.
查尔叔叔给我的 对不起
I'm sorry. Mojo, I love you.
对不起 魔咒 我爱你
No! No! No! No!
不! 不! 不! 不!
Oh, my God.
哦 上帝
No, you're a good dog! Good dog! Good dog!
好狗 好狗 好狗!
Whoa! Hey, hey, hey! All right! Oh! No! No!
喔 好吧! 好吧!
Okay. Please, please don't kill me!
求求你 别杀我!
I'm sorry! Take the keys! I don't want them!
对不起 钥匙给你了 我不要了!
Car's yours!
车是你的了!
Listen, listen, listen.
听着 听着 听着
- Good, you're here. - Let me see your hands!
- 真好 你们来了 - 把手举起来!
- No, no, no! It's not me! - Let me see your hands.
- 不不不 不是我 - 把手举起来让我看到
The guy's inside.
那个人在里面
Shut up! Walk towards the car.
住嘴 走向警车
Put your head on the hood.
把头顶到引擎罩上
Whoever did this finally managed...
他们终于还是侵入了...
to infiltrate our defense network,
我们的防卫网
which is what they tried to do in Qatar,
他们当时尝试侵入我们的卡塔尔基地
only this time it worked.
不过这次他们得逞了
- What did they get? - We still don't know.
- 他们都弄到了什么? - 目前还未知
Talk to me about the virus.
告诉我病毒的情况
It's a Spider-bot virus.
是一种蜘蛛型病毒
We're not sure what it's going to do,
我们还不了解它的作用
but it may cripple the system.
不过有可能会侵害我们的系统
- Can we stop it? - Every time we try an antivirus,
- 我们能阻止它吗? - 每一次我们想消灭它
it adapts and speeds up.
它会变种而躲过
It's like it's not a virus anymore.
好像不单纯是一种病毒了
It's become the system.
变成了系统
Obviously the first phase of...
很明显 这是大规模...
a major attack against the US.
反美攻击的第一阶段
The only countries with this kind of capability
有此能力的国家包括
are Russia, North Korea, maybe China.
俄罗斯 北朝鲜 也许还有中国
I'm sorry, that's not correct.
抱歉 我想事情不是这样的
Excuse me, young lady.
对不起 女士
I didn't see you standing there. You would be who?
我没留意你在场 你是...?
I'm just the analyst who detected the hack.
是我侦测到他们的攻击
Hold on. It was you? You did it?
等一下 是你侦测到的?
- Her team. - Sir, I was just trying to say,
- 她的团队 - 长官 我只是想说明
they hacked your firewall in 10 seconds.
他们在10秒之内就攻破了我们的防火墙
Okay. Even a supercomputer with a brute force attack
就算是最尖端最具攻击性的计算机
would take 20 years to do that.
也需要至少二十年的时间才能做到
Maybe you can explain, then,
那么我想...
how our latest satellite imagery...
请你给我解释
shows North Korea doubling its naval activity?
北朝鲜加倍了他们的国防?
Maybe it's a precaution,
也许这只是他们的防护措施?
because isn't that what we're doing?
我们不是也一样?
The signal pattern is learning.
信号图像正在不断发展
It's evolving on its own.
他们具有自发进化的能力
And you need to move past Fourier transfers
这不是傅立叶变换(线性变换) 所能解释的了
and start considering quantum mechanics.
已经提升到量子力学的范畴
There is nothing on Earth that complex.
在这个地球上并不存在如此复杂的东西
What about an organism? A living organism?
那么有机体呢? 具有生命能力的有机体
Maybe some kind of DNA-based computer?
例如DNA构成的计算机?
And I know that that sounds crazy...
我知道这个听起来是天方夜谭...
That's enough. That's enough.
够了 够了
We have six floors of...
我们拥有六层楼的同仁
analysts working on this thing.
在协力分析调查这个
Now, if you can find proof to back up your theory,
如果你能找到证据来支持你的观点
I'm gonna be happy to listen to you. But...
我乐意听取你的意见 可是...
if you don't get a filter on that brain-mouth thing,
如果你继续在这里信口开河
you're gonna be off the team. You understand?
就请你走人 听清楚了?
Look, I can't be any clearer
听着 我当时非常清醒
than how crystal clear I am being.
简直"至清无鱼"
- It just stood up. - It just stood up.
- 他就那么站起来了 - 站了起来
Wow. That's really neat.
哇...好恐怖哦
Okay, chiefie.
好吧 这个拿去
Time to fill her up. And no drippy-drippy.
把这个灌满 别滴的到处都是
What are you rolling?
你嗑的什么药?
Whippets?
氧化亚氮(笑气)
Goofballs? A little wowie sauce with the boys?
巴比妥? 还是少许大麻?
- No, I'm not on any drugs. - What's these?
- 我没有嗑药 - 这是什么?
Found it in your pocket. "Mojo."
你口袋里找到的 "魔咒"
Is that what the kids are doing now?
你们小孩现在流行吃这个?
Little bit of Mojo?
"魔咒"?
Those are my dog's pain pills.
那是我狗狗的止痛药
You know, a Chihuahua. A little...
你知道...吉娃娃...
What was that?
怎么回事?
You eyeballing my piece, 50 Cent?
你在盯着我的枪 想当"50分"?
You wanna go? Make something happen. Do it.
想试试? 那你就动一下试试!
'Cause I promise you I will bust you up.
不过我告诉你 我一定会让你开花
Are you on drugs?
你是不是嗑药了?
Let's hope this telephone line works.
但愿这条电话线还管用
Hey, heads up!
嘿 抬头!
Heads up! Hey! Heads up!
抬头! 嘿! 抬头!
What the heck was that?
怎么回事?
English, dude. English.
说英语啊 老弟
Whoa!
喔!
Watch out!
当心!
- Open fire! - Contact! Contact!
- 开火! - 靠近了! 靠近了!
Everybody, quiet. Settle.
大家安静
Whoa, mother... What the hell is...
哦 妈呀 什么玩意?
Get up! Get up! Come on!
快起来 快跑!
Go! Move it!
快跑!
Take cover!
找掩护!
Fig! Cover the rear!
菲格 保护后面!
Cover fire! Move it! Fig, cover the rear!
开火! 快! 菲格 保护后面!
Epps! Cover the rear! Move it!
埃普斯 保护后面!
Come on! Give me a mag!
快! 给我把机枪!
Where's your papa? Where's your papa?
你爸爸呢? 你爸爸呢?
Papa!
爸爸!
Sir, we need... I need a telephone.
先生 我们需要电话
- Telephone, telephone, yes! - Telephone!
- 电话 电话 对! - 电话!
Hey, I need a mag! Give me a mag!
嘿 我给我把机枪!
- Cell phone! - I don't know how to thank you
- 手机! - 真谢谢你
Fire!
开火!
This is an emergency Pentagon call!
帮我接五角大楼 紧急电话!
I need you to... Do you understand?
我要你...听到吗?
It's an emergency Pentagon...
这是紧急...
I don't have a credit card!
我没有信用卡!
Sir, the attitude is not going to...
先生 你的态度根本...
speed things up any bit at all.
无法提高办事效率
I'm going to ask you to speak...
请你对着话筒...
into the mouthpiece very clearly.
把话说清楚
I'm in the middle of a war!
我正在打仗!
This is frigging ridiculous!
这真他妈荒唐!
Ammo!
弹药!
I need a credit card!
我需要张信用卡!
- Epps! Where's your wallet? - Pocket!
- 埃普斯! 你的钱包呢? - 口袋里
- Which pocket? - My back pocket!
- 哪个口袋? - 屁股口袋里!
You got 10 back pockets!
你有那么多屁股口袋!
Left cheek! Left cheek! Left cheek!
左边屁股! 左边屁股!
All right, keep shooting! Keep shooting!
好的 继续射击!
Okay, it's Visa.
好了 是VISA卡
Also, sir, have you heard about
还有 先生 您听说过
our premium plus world-service gold package?
我们的 "至尊全球服务"超值套餐吗?
No, I don't want a premium package!
不 我不要什么超值套餐!
Epps! Pentagon!
埃普斯! 五角大楼!
Give me a status.
报告情况
Sir, we're tracking a...
长官 我们追踪到一支
Special Ops team under fire in Qatar.
在卡塔尔遭受攻击的特种部队
They say they're survivors of the base attack.
他们说是基地袭击的幸存者
Survivors?
幸存者?
I ain't never seen this in my life!
我这辈子还没见过这东西!
Need gunships on station ASAP!
需要武装直升机立即支援!
Predator's coming up in a minute.
掠食者马上赶到
We're linking the call to the nearest AWACS.
我们正联系最近的空中预警机
Unknown, man. I don't...
不知道 伙计 我不...
Man, if you seen this shit...
伙计 如果你看到这玩意儿...
Predator ETA two minutes.
掠食者预计两分钟后到达
Hey! Make way!
嘿! 让开!
- What is that? - I don't know.
- 这是什么? - 我不知道
We need air support and we need it now.
我们现在就需要空中支援
Roll in strike package Bravo on unknown target.
对不明物体进行密集型致命打击
I authenticate Tango Whiskey at time 0300 Zulu.
敌我鉴别代码TW0300Z
Attention, all aircraft.
所有空军注意
This will be a danger close-fire mission.
这将是次危险的近距离攻击任务
Weapons, I just got a call from Falcon Ops.
武器 我刚刚接到猎鹰特种队的电话
Who's closer to Kill Box One Alpha?
谁离目的地比较近?
- Send the Hogs, sir. - Okay, send the Hogs over
- 贪婪者 长官 - 好的
to Kill Box One Alpha. It's a danger close...
派贪婪者去 这是次危险的...
Switch the Hogs to Kill Box One Alpha,
派贪婪者前往目的地
300 feet danger close.
高度300英尺
Friendlies in the area.
目标在地面
Seven-man team north of orange smoke!
南部的橘色烟标识的是我们的7人小队!
Received Kill Box One Alpha. Engage hostile.
到达指定区域 可以攻击
Attack direction west! You're clear and hot!
攻击西面 目标明显!
Strike, tell me status of Hog right now.
攻击 报告贪婪者的情况
Hog One-One Dark Star status.
贪婪者一号 暗星一号 报告情况
- Lennox! The heat's coming! - Laze the target!
- 兰诺斯! 破甲弹来了! - 快引导目标!
We got a beam-rider incoming! Laze target!
我们发射了激光制导导弹! 引导目标!
- Ready! Heat's coming! - What? Bring it!
- 准备! 破甲弹来了! - 什么? 引导它啊!
Receiving radar jamming in vicinity of target.
在目标附近受到雷达干扰
No frigging way that thing's still not down
他妈没办法干掉那东西了
Spooky Three Two, use 105 shells. Bring the rain.
幽灵32号 使用105毫米弹 密集攻击
Be advised, ground team...
地面部队请求...
is requesting 105 sabot rounds.
使用105火炮
Did we lose them?
干掉了吗?
Warthog One confirm visual on friendlies.
疣猪1号确认目标被消灭
Where's Fig?
菲格在哪?
- Fig? Fig? - Oh, God!
- 菲格! 菲格! - 啊 上帝!
- God damn it! - Get a medic!
- 该死的! - 找医生来!
Get a medic!
找医生来!
- I'm sorry. - Black Hawk...
- 对不起 - 黑鹰...
We'll get a medic. Just hold on. He's got a pulse
医生来了 坚持住 他脉搏微弱
We need a medevac. One man down.
我们需要救伤直升机 一人重伤
Patient care category urgent
需要立即治疗
Bring them home.
带他们回家
You get those men stateside right now.
立即带他们回本土
I want them debriefed in 10 hours.
让他们在10小时之内向我汇报
There's only one hacker in the world...
这世上只有一个黑客...
who can break this code.
能破解这代码
Hey! Hey, hey, hey! Wait! Stop!
嘿! 等等! 停下来!
I am sorry to bother you.
很抱歉打搅你
- Maggie? - Listen, I need your help.
- 玛吉? - 听着 我需要你的帮助
No! This is my private area,
不 这是我的私人场所
my place of Zen and peace.
我的禅静之所
- Listen to me. - Glen! Who is it?
- 听我说 - 格伦 是谁啊?
Shut up, Grandma!
闭嘴 奶奶!
What are you doing here?
你来这里干什么?
Just give me a break, will you, please?
帮我个忙 好吗 拜托?
Grandmama! Drink your prune juice!
奶奶! 喝你的果汁去吧!
- What level are you on, man? - Six.
- 打到几级了 伙计? - 六级
Oh, here come the matrix! Here come the matrix!
喔 老大来了
Glen, seriously,
格伦 说真的
don't you want to see something classified?
你不是想看"机密"吗?
Yeah. Get low.
耶 低点
Here we go. Here we go. Double tap.
很好 很好 双击
Hey, I just paused it. I just paused it.
嘿 我暂停了
Hey. I need a moment.
嘿 给我几分钟
- Please. - Sorry.
- 拜托 - 对不起
Hey, man, save my game.
嘿 伙计 帮我存档
How classified?
有多机密?
Like "I will go to jail for the rest...
是那种我要是给你看
"of my life for showing you" classified.
下半辈子就要在牢里过的机密
Yes! One quick peek.
耶! 就看一眼!
Special Ops got a thermal snapshot...
袭击我们卡塔尔基地的怪物
of whatever hit the base in Qatar.
被我们的特种部队拍了照
I want to see it.
我想看看
Well, the imager was damaged, sir.
相机已经被毁坏了 长官
The rangers are en route with the imager,
工作人员正在尝试修复相机
but we also have a security issue.
但我们现在还有个安全隐患
Circle logs indicate one of the analysts...
记录显示某个分析师
made a copy of the network intrusion signal.
拷贝了入侵信号
The signal strength is through the roof.
信号能量真是太高了
Where did you say you got this?
你说你是从哪弄到的?
It hacked the national military...
他在不到一分钟的时间
air-guard frequency in less than a minute.
入侵国家军事安全防卫系统
- No way. - Yeah
- 怎么可能! - 是的
Looks like there's a message embedded in the signal.
看上去在这信号中还暗藏着信息
Let me work my magic.
我终于可以大显身手了
"Project Iceman"?
"冰人计划"?
- What's Sector Seven? - Who is Captain Witwicky?
- 什么是第七区组织? - 维特维奇船长又是谁?
Are you playing those video games again?
你又在玩游戏了?
Cops! Cops!
警察! 警察!
FBI! Clear right!
FBI! 让开!
Lock it down! Lock it down!
把他抓住! 把他抓住!
Cops!
警察!
Lock it down.
把他抓住
Wait! I'm just a cousin! I'm just a...
等等! 我是无辜的! 我是...
Get off my Grandmama's carpet!
别踩我奶奶的地毯!
She don't like nobody on the carpet!
她不喜欢人踩她的地毯!
Especially police!
尤其是警察!
It was an awesome spectacle here an hour ago
一个小时之前有超过40架C-17
when over 40 C-17 s lifted off of this very base.
运输机由此基地升空 场面颇为壮观
We're not told where they're going.
目的地尚未获知
Morning, Mo.
早上好
The government has been very quiet about...
政府方面对于发生的情况...
what's going on but in our...
也是三缄其口
- Mojo. Mojo. - They were headed directly
- 魔咒 魔咒 - 他们直接朝着
towards North Korea.
北韩方向前进
Stop with the barking, Mojo. It's too early. Please?
别这么早就开始叫唤 好吗 魔咒?
Miles? Miles, listen to me. Listen.
迈尔斯 迈尔斯 听着
My car, it stole itself, okay?
我的车 它自己跑了
What are you talking about, man?
你在胡说些什么呢 伙计?
Satan's Camaro. In my yard. It's stalking me.
在我家院子里 那辆着魔的卡马洛追着我不放
Stop!
停下!
No, no, no, no, no, no.
不 不 不
Oh, my God!
啊 我的天!
Sam?
山姆?
Hi.
嗨
That was... That was really awesome.
你这个...很有型啊
- Well, it felt awesome. - Are you okay?
- 噢 是很有型 - 你没事吧?
I'm not okay, all right?
我不太好
I'm losing my mind a little bit.
我快要抓狂了
I'm getting chased by my car right now. I got to go.
我正被我的车追呢 我得跑路了
You know what?I'm gonna catch up with you guys later
我一会儿再去找你们
Oh, great. Cops.
太好了 是警察
Officer!
长官!
Listen!
听我说!
Oh, that hurt.
啊 真疼
Thank God you're here! I've had the worst day ever!
感谢上帝 你在这里! 我从没这么惨过!
I've been... I've been followed here...
我骑着我妈的自行车
on my mother's bike! Right?
被一路追踪到这里
And my car's right there...
我的车就在那儿
and it's been following me here!
它一路追着我到这里!
So get out of the car!
下车啊!
No! Stop! Oh, God. Okay, okay! Okay, all right!
不! 停下! 啊 上帝 好吧 好吧 够了!
Okay! I'm sorry! I'm...
够了! 对不起! 我...
I didn't mean to hit your car! Look!
我没想碰你的车!
Okay, look, look, look! Stop, stop!
好的 听着 停下 停下!
Please! Okay, what do you want from me?
求你了 你想要什么?
Okay.
好的
Oh, God, no! No!
啊 上帝 不 不!
Oh, shit! Oh, shit, shit, shit! Oh, God! Oh, shit!
啊 该死 啊 该死! 上帝 该死!
It's a bad dream.
真是噩梦!
Are you username LadiesMan217?
你的用户名是不是"万人迷先生217"?
I don't know what you're talking about!
你在说什么?
Yeah.
是啊
Where is eBay item 21153?
你在易趣的拍卖物品21153在哪?
Where are the glasses?
眼镜在哪?
Get back!
退后!
Stop!
停车!
God!
上帝!
What is your problem, Sam?
你怎么了 山姆?
Okay, there's a monster right there!
那里有个怪物
It just attacked me!
刚刚袭击了我!
Here he comes!
又来了!
All right, get up. Get up and run!
快起来 起来快跑
You have to run! Okay.
你快跑
Sam, what is that thing?
山姆 那个是什么?
You have to get in the car. Get in.
你快上车 上车
I don't want to.
我可不想
- Get in the car. Trust me. Trust me! - Sam
- 上车 相信我 相信我! - 山姆
Get in! Go, go, go, go, go.
上车 快 快 快!
Go, go, go, go!
快 快 快!
Oh, God! We're gonna die! We're gonna die!
啊 上帝 我们要死了 我们要死了!
No, we're not. No, we're not gonna die.
不 不会的 我们不会死
- Oh, my God! - Trust me. He's a kick-ass driver!
- 啊 上帝! - 相信我 他很厉害!
Oh, my God! No!
啊 我的天 不!
We're gonna die!
我们要死了!
Oh, my God!
啊 我的天!
We're locked in.
我们被锁在里面了
The car won't start.
车也无法发动
At least we ditched the monster, right?
至少我们躲开了怪物 对吧?
Okay.
好的
Time to start.
时机到了
He's got me! Oh, God!
他要抓住我了 上帝
He's going to kill me!
他会杀了我的!
No. No, no, no!
不 不 不!
Get off!
下来!
Kill it! Kill it!
杀了它! 杀了它!
Get it, get it, get it, get it!
抓住它 抓住它 抓住它
Not so tough without a head, are you?
没了头就不行了吧?
Here, come on.
来 过来
What is it?
这是什么?
It's a robot.
是机器人
But like a...
但是像...
Like a different...
是另一种...
You know, like a super-advanced robot.
超级先进的机器人
It's probably Japanese.
大概是日本机器人
Yeah, it's definitely Japanese.
对 肯定是日本的
What are you doing?
你现在怎么办?
I don't think it wants to hurt us.
我想他不会伤害我们
It would have done that already.
他要是想的话 一定一早就动手了
Really? Well, do you speak robot?
真的吗? 你会讲机器人语吗?
Because they just had,
因为他们俩刚刚...
like, a giant droid death match.
进行了一场生死决斗
I think it wants something from me.
我觉得我有他要的东西
What?
什么?
Well, 'cause the other one...
因为另外一个...
was talking about my eBay page.
跟我提过我的易趣网页
You are the strangest boy I have ever met.
你真是我见过的最无厘头的人
- Can you talk? - XM Satellite Radio...
- 你会说话吗? - 卫星收音机
Digital cable brings you...
数字广播系统...
Columbia Broadcasting System...
哥伦比亚广播系统...
So you... You talk through the radio?
你是通过广播讲话?
Thank you, you're beautiful.
谢谢你 你很漂亮
You're wonderful, you're wonderful.
你太棒了 太棒了
So, what was that last night? What was that?
那...昨晚是怎么回事? 那是什么?
Message from Starfleet, Captain...
来自浩渺宇宙的...
Throughout the inanimate vastness of space...
星河舰队长官的讯息...
Angels will rain down like visitors from heaven!
太空访客会如天使般成群降临
Hallelujah!
哈利路亚!
Visitors from heaven? What...
太空访客? 什么...
What are you, like, an alien or something?
你是什么 是外星人还是...?
Any more questions you want to ask?
还有别的问题吗?
He wants us to get in the car.
他要我们上车
And go where?
可是去哪儿呢?
Fifty years from now,
50年之后
when you're looking back at your life,
当你回望今生
don't you want to be able to say...
你想后悔当初...
you had the guts to get in the car?
没胆上这辆车吗?
This car's a pretty good driver.
这车是个不错的司机呢
I know.
我知道
Why don't you go sit in that seat, there?
你为什么不坐在驾驶位上?
I'm not going to sit in that seat. He's driving.
我才不要坐那 他在开呢
Yeah.
嗯
You're right.
你说得对
- Well, maybe you should sit in my lap. - Why?
- 要么你坐在我膝盖上? - 为什么?
Well, I have the only seat belt here.
这里只有一个安全带
You know, safety first.
安全第一嘛
- Yeah, all right. - Right?
- 嗯 好吧 - 行吗?
- Yeah. - Okay.
- 当然 - 好的
There, see? That's better.
看 好多了吧
- Okay. - Okay
- 好的 - 好的
You know, that seat belt thing...
你这个"安全带"之计
was a pretty smooth move.
还使得蛮圆滑嘛
Thank you.
谢谢
You know what I don't understand?
其实我想不通
Why, if he's supposed to be,
他既然这么厉害
like, this super-advanced robot,
是个超级先进的机器人
does he transform back into...
为什么还要变回...
this piece-of-crap Camaro?
这么一坨烂车?
Whoa! Whoa!
哇! 哇!
Oh, see? No. Get... No, that doesn't work. See?
你看 这样不行 看见没?
Move it, you moron!
开走!你个混蛋!
Great, now... See?
这下好了...看见没?
Fantastic.
太妙了
Now you pissed him off.
你把他气跑了
That car is sensitive.
这个车很敏感的
I mean, $4000 just drove off.
我的4000美金就这么跑了
What?
这是...?
This is you...
这是你...
Oh, my God!
啊 我的天!
Come on, let's go.
上来 我们走
This is the coolest thing I've ever seen!
这是我见过最酷的事情
Explosions everywhere!
到处都在爆炸!
This is easily a hundred times cooler...
比《世界末日》还要劲爆...
than Armageddon. I swear to God!
一百倍! 我对天发誓!
Fire, fire, fire, fire!
着火了 着火了!
Whoa! Sweet!
啊 天!
Oh, dude, I hope this guy's got asteroid insurance,
啊 老弟 我希望这家伙交了陨石险
'cause he is so boned!
因为他太惨了!
What is that?
那是什么?
There's something in the tree, dude.
树上有东西 伙计
No, there's something in the thing by the tree!
不 树旁有什么东西!
Could you guys just give me a space rock?
你们能给我一块陨石吗?
Excuse me, are you the tooth fairy?
对不起 请问你是不是牙仙?
Hey, sweetheart,
嘿 宝贝
what are you doing out here by yourself?
你怎么一个人在这儿!
Holy God! What happened to the pool?
我的天哪! 游泳池怎么了!
Are you Samuel James Witwicky,
你是不是山姆·詹姆斯·维特维奇
descendent of Archibald Witwicky?
阿切邦·维特维奇的后代?
They know your name.
他们知道你的名字
Yeah.
嗯
My name is Optimus Prime.
我叫擎天柱
We are autonomous robotic...
我们是来自...
organisms from the planet Cybertron.
塞伯坦星球的机械生命体
But you can call us Autobots for short.
也可以简称为汽车人
Autobots.
汽车人
What's cracking, little bitches?
什么是"超辣的辣妹"?
My first lieutenant. Designation, Jazz.
这是我的副手 爵士
This looks like a cool place to kick it.
看来这地方挺有型
What is that? How did he learn to talk like that?
你哪里学来的这种调子?
We've learned Earth's languages...
我们从互联网上...
through the World Wide Web.
学到地球人的语言
My weapons specialist, Ironhide.
这是我的武器专家 铁皮
- You feeling lucky, punk? - Easy, Ironhide.
- 今天你感到好运降身吗 小子? - 别吓人了 铁皮
Just kidding. I just wanted to show him my cannons.
开玩笑啦 只是想给他秀一下我的大炮
Our medical officer, Ratchet.
我们的医学专家 救护车
The boy's pheromone level suggests...
你身上的激素水平
he wants to mate with the female.
显示你想跟这位女士亲热
You already know your guardian, Bumblebee.
这位是你的守护者 你已经认识了 大黄蜂
Bumblebee, right?
大黄蜂 对吧?
Check on the rep Yep, second to none.
检测系统 嗯 挺好的
So you're my guardian, huh?
你就是我的守护者 哈?
His vocal processors were damaged in battle.
他的发声系统在战斗受到破坏
I'm still working on them.
我在想办法把他治好
Why are you here?
你们为什么在这里?
We are here looking for the All Spark.
我们是来找火种源的
And we must find it before Megatron.
而且一定要抢在威震天前面
Mega-what?
威什么?
Our planet was once a powerful empire,
我们的星球曾是一个强大的帝国
peaceful and just,
平静祥和
until we were betrayed by Megatron,
直到有一天 威震天出卖了我们
leader of the Decepticons.
他是霸天虎的首领
All who defied them were destroyed.
不服从他们的势力都被消灭
Our war finally consumed the planet,
而我们的星球也在战争中消逝殆尽
and the All Spark was lost to the stars.
火种源也消失在星际之间
Megatron followed it to Earth,
威震天尾随它来到地球
where Captain Witwicky found him.
正是在那里维特维奇船长发现了他
My grandfather
我的曾祖父
It was an accident that intertwined our fates.
那是一个意外 却把我们的命运纠缠在一起
Come back!
回来!
I think the dogs have found something.
它好像找到了什么
The ice is cracking!
冰面开裂了!
Captain! Grab my rope, Captain!
船长! 抓住绳子 船长!
I'm all right, lads!
我没事 伙计们!
Can we throw you a rope, Captain?
要给你扔条绳子吗 船长?
Megatron crash-landed...
威震天在拿到能量体之前
before he could retrieve the Cube.
坠落到地球上了
Men! We've made a discovery!
伙计们! 我们有个重大发现!
He accidentally activated his navigation system.
他无意中启动了它的导航系统
The coordinates to the Cube's location on Earth
能量体在地球上的座标
were imprinted on his glasses.
由此印在了他的镜片上
How'd you know about his glasses?
你怎么知道眼镜的?
- eBay. - eBay
- 易趣网 - 哦 易趣网
If the Decepticons find the All Spark,
如果霸天虎们找到了火种源
they will use its power to transform...
他们就会用它的能量转换...
Earth's machines and build a new army.
地球上的机器 建立新的军队
And the human race will be extinguished.
届时人类便会灭亡
Sam Witwicky, you hold the key to Earth's survival.
山姆·维特维奇 地球的存亡就掌握在你的手上了
Please tell me that you have those glasses.
眼镜还在你那儿吧?
It's like a self-regenerating molecular armor.
这简直就是个能自我修复的装甲
Look at the scorch mark where the sabot round hit.
看看脱壳穿甲弹打的弹孔
Melted right through.
直穿而过
Hey, aren't sabots hot-Ioaded for,
穿甲弹是不是可以...
like, a 6,000-degree magnesium burn?
产生6000度的高温
Close to it. It melts tank armor.
很接近 能烧熔坦克装甲
So this metal skin must react to extreme heat.
因此它的金属表面一定会在极高温下有反应
- Heads up! - Oh!
- 注意! - 啊!
I thought you said that thing was dead, man!
你不是说这鬼东西已经死了吗!
Strap it down! Strap it! This thing is wicked.
捆住它! 捆住! 这东西很邪门!
All right, get on the horn with Northern Command.
好的 联系北方司令部
Tell them that our effective weapon...
告诉他们我们的有效武器...
is high-heat sabot rounds.
是高温穿甲弹
Recommend we load them on all the gunships. Go.
建议所有的直升机都配备这种弹药 去吧!
You want that piece?
这块你要不要?
Okay, Maggie, look.
玛吉 你听我说
Let me break it down to you how it's gonna happen.
我告诉你接下来会怎样
They gonna come through that door...
等下进来的人
and be good cop, bad cop.
肯定有唱黑脸 有唱白脸
Don't fall for that, all right?
别中圈套 好吗?
That's why I ate their food.
所以我才吃这些东西
See, they put the plate of...
看吧 他们把吃的放这儿
donuts out here to test your guilt.
是要试探你是不是心虚
If you don't touch it, you're guilty.
如果你不吃 就说明你心虚
I ate the whole plate. The whole plate. Okay?
所以我整盘都吃啦 整盘!
It's me and you.
就咱俩
They walk through that door, you don't say nothing.
他们进来时 你什么也别说
She did it! She did it!
是她干的! 是她干的!
She's the one you want! All right?
她才是你们要抓的人!
I was just sitting at home watching cartoons,
我只是在家看卡通片
playing video games with my cousin,
还有跟我堂弟玩游戏而已
and she came in there.
然后她闯了进来
- And then... - Glen, you freak.
- 然后... - 格伦 你个混蛋
Hey! I am not going to jail for you or anybody else!
我才不会因为你或任何人去坐牢!
I have done nothing bad my entire life!
我这辈子从来没干过坏事!
Hey, man, I'm still a virgin.
老兄 我还是个童男呢!
Okay, so what?
好吧 那又怎样?
I've downloaded a couple of...
我是从互联网上...
thousand songs off the Internet.
下载了几千首歌
Who hasn't? Who hasn't?
可是谁没有呢!
- I promise! - Glen, shut up!
- 我发誓! - 格伦 闭嘴!
No, you shut up! Don't talk to me!
不 你闭嘴! 不要跟我说话!
Don't talk to me, criminal!
不要跟我说话 你这个罪犯!
Oh, sugar rush.
噢 给糖甜昏了头
This is... This is not his fault.
不是 不是他的错
See? So can I go home now?
她都说了 我能回家了吗?
- Oh, okay. I won't. - But just listen to me.
- 好吧 我不会了 - 请你 请你听我说
Okay, whoever hacked into your military system
不管是谁黑了你们的防卫系统
downloaded a file, all right?
并且下载了一个文件
It was something about someone named Witwicky
应该是跟一个名叫维特维奇的人有关
and some government group, right?
还有一个政府组织
Named Sector Seven.
叫做第七区组织
You have to let me talk to Defense Secretary Keller
请你让我先跟国防部长谈谈
before you go to war with the wrong country!
否则你们很可能跟错误的敌人作战!
Whatever fell out of the sky ended up right behind
"不管天上掉了什么 它就落在..."
- What did he say? - What?
- 他怎么说? - 什么?
Did he hear it, too?
他也听到了吗?
Yeah, Jack heard it, too. Yeah.
是 杰克也听到了
What does he think it is?
他说是什么?
He thinks it's a military experiment.
他以为是军事实验
What a knucklehead.
简直不知所谓
Yeah, well, I think it's a plane.
对 我觉得是一架飞机...
Still no official word as to what happened. You...
"目前官方尚未发布任何意见..."
Call Sam.
打电话给山姆
- Yeah. Why? - He should be home in 15 minutes.
- 嗯 为什么? - 15分钟之内他该到家
Well, I'll call him in 15 minutes.
我15分钟之内打电话给他
If you wait 15 minutes,
如果你再等15分钟
he'll be late and you'll have to ground him.
那他就晚了 你就得要禁他的足了
Well, I can't ground him if he's not late, can I?
如果他没有晚 我就不能禁他 对吧?
I need you to stay here, all right?
你就呆在这儿 知道吗?
You got to stay here and you're gonna watch them.
你要呆在这儿看着他们
- Okay, okay. - All of them.
- 好的 好的 - 所有的人
- Do you hear what I'm saying? - Yeah, okay, okay.
- 明白了吗? - 嗯 嗯 嗯
Five minutes, all right?
就5分钟 好吗?
Thanks for staying on my path.
谢谢你走在了入门径上
Oh, yeah. No, no, Dad. Hey!
哦 不 爸爸...
The... Oh, the path.
啊 入门径
I'm sorry. I forgot about the path.
对不起 我忘记了
I'm gonna sweep the whole thing right now.
我现在就打扫干净
How about that?
怎么样?
- You know, I buy half your car... - Yeah.
- 要知道我给你买了车...- 嗯
then I bail you out of jail...
把你从警察局保释出来
and then I just decided to do all your chores.
我还打算包了你所有的家务
- The chores. - Yeah. Life is great, huh?
- 家务...- 对啊 生活挺不错嘛 啊?
Life... Life is fantastic, is how good it is.
生活简直无与伦比 太棒了
It's so... Oh, the trash cans.
哦 还有垃圾筒
Sorry, Dad. I'm gonna do the trash cans now.
对不起 爸爸 我马上去倒
No, no, I don't want you to strain yourself.
不 不 我不想累坏你
No, no, I won't strain myself, Dad.
不 不会累的 爸爸
I'll do it.
我去做
It would hurt my feelings if you do it.
如果你那样做 我会很伤心的
- You sure? I don't mind, I... - I promise...
- 你肯定? 我不介意... - 我保证...
No, no, no, I'm gonna do it.
不 不 不 我会去做的
I'm gonna do the trash cans...
我会去倒了垃圾
and I'm gonna scrape the grill...
我还会擦洗烤架
and I'm gonna...
我还要...
I'm gonna sweep up the whole house right now.
我马上就去打扫整个屋子
- Tonight, right now? - Right now.
- 今晚 现在? - 对 现在!
The...
那...
I love you. God, I love you,
我爱你 爸爸
just so much right now.
我此时此刻真是太爱你了
You know, Mom wanted me to ground you.
你妈妈要我把你关在家呢
- You're three minutes late. - Right?
- 你晚回家三分钟了 - 是吗?
Oh, well, just another thing you did for me, Dad,
哦 你看 你又为我做了一件事 爸爸!
because you're such a swell guy,
你真是太好了
One more thing, huh?
又一件事 哈?
All right, I love you! Sleep good, handsome man!
好了 我爱你 睡个好觉 帅哥!
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你干嘛? 你这是干嘛?
No, watch the path! Watch the path!
不 注意门径 注意门径!
Watch the... Please, please, please.
注意... 拜托 拜托 拜托
No, no, wait. No, no, no! Oh, no!
不 等等 不 不!
- Sorry. My bad. - Oh, I... You couldn't...
- 对不起 我的错 - 啊 我...你不能...
You couldn't wait for five...
你怎么连五分钟...
You couldn't wait for five minutes?
你怎么连五分钟都等不了?
I told you to just stay! Just stay! God!
我说了 呆在那儿! 呆在那儿! 上帝!
I told you to watch them. I told you.
我不是叫你看住他们!
Okay, you know what?
好的 你知道吗?
They seem to be in a little bit of a rush.
他们就是这样急性子啊!
Oh, this is bad. No!
太糟糕了 不!
Mojo, Mojo! Off the robot! God!
魔咒! 魔咒! 别靠近机器人!
- Oh, wet. - No, no, no, no, no! Easy! Easy!
- 啊 湿了 - 不 不 不 冷静 冷静!
Hold on! Hold! This is Mojo. This is Mojo.
住手 住手! 这是魔咒 这是魔咒
He's a pet of mine.
是我的宠物
He's a pet. Okay? That's all.
它是宠物 明白?
If you could just put the guns away...
如果你能收起你的武器...
Put the... Put them away. Please.
收起它们 拜托
You have a rodent infestation.
你有只啮齿动物
- A what? - Shall I terminate?
- 一只什么? - 要不要摧毁?
No, no, no, no. He's not a rodent, he's a Chihuahua.
不 不 不 它不是啮齿动物 它只是吉娃娃
This is my... This is my Chihuahua.
这是我的吉娃娃
We love Chihuahuas! Don't we?
我们都爱吉娃娃 对不对?
He's leaked lubricants all over my foot.
他撒了我满脚润滑剂!
- He peed on you? Bad Mojo. Bad Mojo! - Bad Mojo!
- 他在你脚上撒尿? 坏魔咒! 坏魔咒! - 坏魔咒!
I'm sorry. He's got a male dominance thing.
对不起 它只是想表明这是它的领地
That's all it is.
仅此而已
- My foot's gonna rust. - All right.
- 我的脚要生锈了 - 没事的
Okay, okay.
好的 好的
- Shut up and go hide! - Just hurry.
- 闭嘴 去躲起来! - 快!
Autobots, recon.
汽车人 进行侦察
I hope he's okay. He's in the kitchen.
我希望他没事 他正在厨房里
Got some ice on his nose.
在往他的鼻子上敷冰呢
I had to slap him around a little bit.
我刚刚小小地教训了他一下
You did not.
你才没有呢
- You didn't even ground him. - Almost, almost.
- 你甚至没有禁他足 - 差不多 差不多了
Where are they? No, no, no, no, no.
他们在哪里? 不 不 不
Come on, come on.
拜托 拜托
- What? What is this? - Time is short.
- 什么 这是什么? - 时间宝贵
They really want those glasses.
他们真的很想要那副眼镜
Come on. What are you doing?
拜托 你在干什么?
- I'm gonna help you. - Okay.
- 我想要帮你 - 好的
- Please hurry. - Okay.
- 请快点 - 好的
Yeah, no, no. It's definitely gone.
啊 不 真的不见了
What do you mean?
怎么会呢?
My glasses were in the bag.
眼镜在袋子里
They were in the backpack...
袋子在我背包里
and now the backpack isn't here.
但背包不在这里
Well, they're gonna be pissed,
他们肯定不会高兴的
so what do you wanna do?
现在怎么办?
So what I think you should do is you should...
我觉得你应该...
You should check this whole...
你应该清查下整个...
This whole section here.
这里每个角落
Just give it a clean sweep,
你帮我仔细找找
and I'll get the corner here.
我找这边的角落
Yeah, no, no, no. Not there.
不 不 那里不要
That's my... That's my private...
那边是我私人的...
- Sorry. That's nothing. - You just...
- 对不起 没什么 - 你只是...
- You just told me to look... - I know,
- 你只是叫我找... - 我明白
but I didn't mean to look inside...
但我又没叫你...
of my treasure chest.
翻我的藏宝箱
You should be way more specific...
你应该讲清楚
so I don't get in trouble in your room.
不然我又会找错地方...
I'm already stressed out enough.
我已经都快崩溃了
Okay. What now?
又怎么了?
No. No, no. No, no, no.
不 不 不
This isn't hiding. This isn't hiding.
这算什么躲藏? 这算什么躲藏?
This is my backyard, not a truck stop.
这里是我家后院 可不是公路休息站
Oh, God. Oh!
啊 上帝 啊!
Okay, I saw it.
我看到了
The UFO landed right here and now it's gone.
不明飞行物体在此着陆 但现在不见了
My moped's under there, man!
我的摩托还在底下压着 伙计!
Who's gonna pay for that?
谁来赔我钱?
Sam? Sam, Sam, Sam, Sam.
山姆 山姆?
He's back here.
他又来了
I can't deal with this. I can't...
我处理不了 我...
What? Oh, no, no, no.
什么? 噢 不 不
This is my mother's flower...
这是我妈的花园
Okay, listen. You got to listen to me.
听着 听我说
If my parents come out here and see you,
如果我父母出来看到了你们
they're gonna freak out.
他们会吓坏了的
My mother's got a temper, okay?
我妈脾气很不好
We must have the glasses.
我们必须拿到那副眼镜
I know you need the glasses.
我知道你需要那副眼镜
I've been looking everywhere.
我已经找遍所有地方
They're not here. They're definitely not here.
它们不在这里 很明显不在这里
Keep searching.
继续找
I need you to be quiet for five minutes.
我要你们安静五分钟
Ten minutes. Okay?
或十分钟 好吗?
Please, I'm begging you.
拜托 我求你们了
You got to... You're making a racket.
你们要...你们太吵了
I can't concentrate.
我不能专心
You want me to look and I'm hearing...
你们要我找 我却听到...
Calm down, calm down.
冷静 冷静
You got to do something here.
你得帮帮我
Autobots, fall back.
汽车人 撤退
Thank you. Please, for five minutes.
谢谢你 拜托 就五分钟
Good? Good? Okay
好吗? 好吗?
- Move! - Get away!
- 行动 - 走开!
What's the matter with you? Can't you be quiet?
你们怎么回事? 就不能安静下吗?
He wants us to be quiet.
他要我们安静
Earthquake! Move, move, move, move! Earthquake!
地震了! 快跑! 地震了!
Judy! Judy, get under the table! Move it!
茱蒂 快躲到桌下! 快呀!
Duck and cover right now!
赶快躲起来!
How did you get over there so fast?
你怎么那么快就跑到那里?
Wow! That was tingly!
哇! 好痒!
- You got to try that! - Yeah, that looks fun.
- 你该试试! - 嗯 看上去很好玩
- Sam? - Sammy?
- 山姆? - 山姆?
- What the hell is that? - I don't know.
- 那是什么? - 我不知道
- Sam? - That's weird.
- 山姆? - 真奇怪
- Sam! - Ratchet, point the light.
- 山姆! - 救护车 打开灯
Come on, hurry.
快点
Listen, we got a major issue in here.
听着 这里出了点状况
What's with the light? You gotta stop the light.
开灯干什么 把灯关掉
What's going on? Turn it off.
怎么回事? 把灯关掉
You gotta tell him to shut it off.
让他把灯关掉
- Shut it off. - Sam, are you in there?
- 关掉 - 山姆 你在里面吗?
How come the door's locked?
为何门是锁着的
You know the rules. No doors locked in my house!
你知道规矩的 不许在这家里锁门
You know he'll start counting
你再不开门
- if you don't open the door! - One more chance. Five...
- 他就要开始倒数了! - 最后一次机会 5...
Oh, dear.
哦 天哪
- Four. It's coming off the hinges, pal. - He's counting!
- 4 打开门铰链 - 他在倒数了!
- Sam, just open the door. - Three.
- 山姆 快开门 - 3
- Oh, my. - Two.
- 噢 天啊 - 2
- He's counting. - Stand back.
- 他在倒数 - 退后
What's up? What's with the bat?
怎么了? 你拿着球棒干嘛?
Who were you talking to?
你刚在跟谁讲话?
I'm talking to you.
跟你们呀
Why are you so sweaty and filthy?
你怎么又臭又脏的?
I'm a child. You know, I'm a teenager.
我年轻啊 你懂得 青少年
We heard voices and noises...
我们听到有人声和噪音
and we thought maybe you were...
我们以为你...
It doesn't matter what we thought.
我们怎么想不重要
What was that light?
刚才那灯光是什么?
No, what light? What? There's no light, Dad!
不是 什么灯光? 没什么灯光 老爸!
You got two lights in your hand! That's what it is.
你们手上不就有两个手电筒! 光是从你们这里来的
- Maybe it bounced... - There was light under the door
- 或许就这么反射...- 光是从门缝里出来的
Look, you can't...
听我说 你们不...
You can't just bounce into my room like that.
你们不能就这么闯进我的房间里来
You got to knock. You got to communicate.
你应该先敲门 先沟通
- We knocked for five minutes. - I'm a teenager.
- 我们敲了5分钟了 - 我长大了
- We knocked. - You didn't knock.
- 我们敲门了 - 你们没有
- You were screaming at me, okay? - No.
- 你们是在冲我喊 知道吗? - 没有
This is repression, what you're doing here.
你们现在是在打压我
You're ruining my youth, okay?
你们在蹂躏我的青春 知道吗?
Oh, for Pete's sakes!
哦 老天啊
You are so defensive! Were you masturbating?
你太过激了 你在手淫吗?
- Judy. - Was I...
- 茱蒂 - 我在...
- No, Mom. - Zip it, okay?
- 没有 老妈 - 够了 好吗?
- It's okay. - No, I don't masturbate!
- 没关系的 - 没有 我没有手淫!
That's not something for you to bring up.
那不是你该管的
That's a father-and-son thing, okay?
那是父子间的对话 好不好?
Father-son thing.
父与子的私事
I mean, you don't have to call it that word
我是说 如果你不喜欢...
if that makes you uncomfortable.
这个词的话
You can call it Sam's happy time or...
你可以称它为"山姆的快乐时间"
- Happy time? - my special alone time...
- 快乐时间? - 或"我特别的..."
- Stop. - Mom.
- 别说了 - 老妈
- Judy, stop. - with myself.
- 茱蒂 别说了 - "私人时间"
- Mom, you can't come in and... - I'm sorry.
- 老妈 你不能就这么进来 - 对不起
It's just been a weird night.
今晚有点不自在
I've had a little bit to drink.
我稍微喝了点酒
- No, no, Dad. - Yeah, well, we saw a light.
- 不要 老爸 - 好了 我们的确看到光的
Oh, parents.
哦 父母来了
I don't know where it was, but we saw it.
我不知道在哪儿 但我的确看到了!
Earthquake! It's another one!
地震! 又来了!
Another earthquake! Get in the doorway!
又是地震! 回到走廊里!
- Okay! - Aftershock! Aftershock!
- 好的! - 余震! 余震!
Oh, I hate these.
哦 我不喜欢地震
- Got to ride it out. Ride it out! - Quick, hide.
- 安全第一 安全第一! - 快 藏起来
- Hey, the lights are back on. - Hide? What?
- 嘿 来电了 - 藏起来? 什么?
- Where? - Come on, get out of that tub.
- 藏哪儿? - 拜托 从浴缸里出来吧
Can't you take safety seriously?
你不觉得保命很重要的?
Good Lord, this floor is filthy, Sam.
要命 这地板真脏 山姆
Oh, no! Look at the yard. The yard is destroyed.
噢 不! 你看院子 都毁了
Judy? Better call the city.
茱蒂 打给电力局
We got a blown transformer!
变压器好像爆了
Power pole's sparking all over the place!
电杆火星四射!
Oh, man. Yard's a waste.
天哪! 院子被毁了
Trashed. Gone.
一塌糊涂 完了
- It's a wash. The whole yard. - You're kidding.
- 成洼地了 整个花园 - 你开玩笑
The parents are very irritating.
这对父母很烦人
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Can I take them out?
- 是啊 是啊 - 我能不能处理掉他们?
Ironhide, you know we don't harm humans.
铁皮 你知道我们不能伤害人类的
What is with you?
你在想什么?
Well, I'm just saying we could. It's an option.
我只是说我们是可以 只是一个方案
We heard you talking to somebody, Sam.
我们听到你和别人在说话 山姆
- We wanna know who. - Mom, I told...
- 到底是谁? - 老妈 我说了...
Hi. I'm Mikaela.
你好 我是梅卡拉
I'm a... I'm a friend of Sam's.
我是山姆的朋友
Gosh, you're gorgeous.
天啊 你真漂亮
Isn't that the prettiest girl?
美若天仙 不是吗?
- She can hear you talking, Mom. - Thank you.
- 她听得到你说话 妈 - 谢谢你
Oh, my goodness. I'm sorry you had to...
天啊! 真抱歉让你听到...
hear our little family discussion about...
我们的家庭讨论...
- Sorry that we're bugging you. - Do you have my backpack?
- 抱歉打扰你们了 - 妈 我的背包呢?
- Come on, hon. Let's go. - Oh, it's in the kitchen.
- 来 亲爱的 我们走 - 哦 在厨房里
Oh, yes. Okay. Okay.
哦 太好了
Your mom's so nice.
你妈人真好
I want you to distract my parents while...
你帮我分散我父母的注意
I slip out and get these glasses to them, okay?
我就能溜出去把眼镜交给他们 好吗?
- Ronald Wickity? - It's Witwicky. Who are you?
- 罗纳德·维奇提? - 是维特维奇 你是谁?
We're the government. Sector Seven.
我们是政府机关 第七区的
- Never heard of it. - Never will.
- 从来没听过 - 以后也不会
Your son's the great-grandson...
你儿子是...
of Captain Archibald Wickity, is he not?
阿奇巴尔德·维奇提的曾孙子 对不对?
It's Witwicky.
是维特维奇
May I enter the premises, sir?
我能进屋吗 先生?
Ron, there's guys all over the front yard.
荣恩 前院有好多人
What the heck is going on here?
到底是怎么回事?
Your son filed a stolen car report last night.
你儿子昨晚举报有人偷车
We think it's involved in...
我们认为这关系到...
a national security matter.
国家的安全
- They're ripping up my rose bushes! - National security?
- 他们在拔我的玫瑰! - 国家安全?
That's right. National security.
没错 国家安全
My God, Ron, they're everywhere.
天哪 荣恩 到处都是他们的人
There's guys in suits all around the house!
到处都是穿西装的!
Look at this!
看呀!
Could you stay off the grass?
可不可以别踩我的草坪
Get me a sample and some isotope readings.
给我采取一些同位素的样本
They're pulling bushes out of the ground!
他们把树都拔了!
Good Lord!
老天!
They've got to get their hands off my bush!
不许他们碰我的花!
- Drop the bat, ma'am. - Hey, hey, hey, that's my...
- 请放下你的球棒 女士 - 喂喂喂 那是我的...
I'm carrying a loaded weapon.
我可是带着武器的
But you'd better get those guys out of my garden.
你最好叫你的人离开我的花园
or I am gonna beat the crap out of them!
否则我会狠狠修理他们
Are you experiencing any flu-like symptoms?
你是否有流感的症状?
Aching joints? Fever?
关节疼痛 发烧?
- No! - What is this?
- 没有 - 怎么回事?
How you doing, son? Is your name Sam?
你好呀 小子 你叫山姆吗?
- Yeah. - Well, I need you to come with us.
- 是啊 - 那你得跟我们走一趟
Whoa, way out of line.
喂 那可不行
Sir, I am asking politely. Back off.
先生 我这已经很客气了 退下
- You're not taking my son. - Really?
- 你不能带我儿子走 - 是吗?
You gonna try to get rough with us?
想和我们硬碰硬?
No, but I'm gonna call the cops because...
不 但我会打电话报警 只因为...
there's something fishy going on around here.
这件事太点蹊跷
Yeah. There's something a little fishy about you,
没错 这里是有些不对劲 你...
your son, your little Taco Bell dog...
你儿子 还有扣皮带的狗
and this whole operation you got going on here.
整个组织都有蹊跷
What operation?
什么组织?
That is what we are gonna find out.
我们接下来就知道了
I think direct contact.
我认为是直接接触
- Son? - Yeah.
- 孩子 - 嗯
- Step forward, please. - Just stand?
- 请上前来 - 站着就行?
Fourteen rads.
14单位
Bingo! Tag them and bag them!
找对人了! 把他们贴上标签卷走
If you hurt my dog, I'll kick your ass!
你敢伤我的狗 我就揣你屁股
Get me a sample on that vegetation ASAP!
尽快取得植被上的样本
Sam! Do not say anything, Sam!
山姆 不要开口
- Yeah. - Not a word until we get a lawyer!
- 好的 - 在律师来前一个字都别说!
So,
好了
LadiesMan217
万人迷先生217
That is your eBay username, right?
那是你的易趣帐号名称 对吧
Yeah but,you know,it was a typo and I ran with it.
对 我打错字了 不过就将错就错
What do you make of this?
那这是什么?
My name is Sam Witwicky, okay? And my...
我叫山姆·维特维奇  知道吗? 我的车...
Is that you?
那是你吗?
Yeah, that sounds like LadiesMan.
是啊 那听起来像万人迷先生
Last night at the station,
昨晚在警局
you told the officer your car transformed.
你说你的车变形了
Enlighten me.
能不能解释一下
Well, here's what I said, okay?
你听我说 好吗?
'Cause this is a total misunderstanding...
我车被偷的这一切...
that my car had been stolen...
都是个误会
- Really? - from me, from my home,
- 是吗? - 从我手上 从家里...
but it's fine now because it's back! It came back!
但现在没事了 因为它回来了 已经回来了
- Well, not by itself. - Well, no.
- 不是自己回来的 - 当然不是
Because cars don't do that...
因为车子不会自己回来
because that would be crazy!
因为那太荒唐了!
That's funny. That is so funny.
真好笑 好笑
So what do you kids know about aliens, huh?
你们两个对外星人了解多少?
Oh, you mean, like a Martian? Like what, E. T? No.
你说火星人? ET? 不知道
- It's an urban legend. - Yeah.
- 那只是个传说 - 是啊
You see this?
知道这是什么吗?
This is an...
这是一枚...
I-can-do-whatever-I-want and-get-away-with-it badge.
"为所欲为"徽章
- Right. - I'm gonna lock you up forever.
- 这样 - 我要把你们永远关起来
Oh, God. You know what? Don't listen to him.
哦 老天 我告诉你 别听他的
He's just pissy 'cause he's got to get back...
他生气是因为他回去后
to guarding the mall.
就得去作购物中心的保安
You, in the training bra, do not test me.
你这穿着运动胸罩的 别惹我
Especially with your daddy's parole coming up.
尤其你爸的假释期快到了
What? Parole?
什么? 假释期?
It's nothing.
没什么
Oh, grand theft auto, that ain't nothing?
哦 偷车大盗不算什么?
You know those cars my dad used to teach me to fix?
你知道我爸以前教我修的车...
Well, they... They weren't always his.
那些...不全是他的
You stole cars?
你们偷车?
Well, we couldn't always afford a babysitter,
我们有时请不起保姆
so sometimes he had to take me along.
那时他就会带我一起去
She's got her own juvie record to prove it!
她也有少年犯罪前科
She's a criminal. Criminals are hot!
她是个罪犯! 罪犯真性感!
That'd be a real shame if he had to...
因为你不合作而让他...
rot in jail the rest of his natural life.
下半辈子待在监狱不太好吧?
It is time to talk!
该说实话了
Big! It's big!
好大
Go, go, go, go!
快 快 快 快!
I can't see it! I can't see it!
我看不到! 我看不到!
Shift your weight towards the front!
你们把重心朝前!
All right! All right!
够了! 够了!
You A-holes are in trouble now.
你们这群废柴有麻烦了
Gentlemen, I want to introduce you to my friend,
先生们 让我向你们介绍 我的朋友...
Optimus Prime.
擎天柱
Taking the children was a bad move.
带走这些孩子是错误的选择
Autobots, relieve them of their weapons.
汽车人 卸下他们的武器
Freeze!
不要动!
Give me those!
拿来吧
Hi, there.
你好
You don't seem afraid.
你好像不怕我们
Are you not surprised to see us?
难道你们看到我们不觉得惊讶吗?
Look, there are S-Seven protocols, okay?
第七区有规定 知道吗?
I'm not authorized to communicate with you
我不允许和你交流
except to tell you I can't communicate with you.
不过除了告诉你"我不能和你交流"
- Get out of the car. - All right.
- 下车 - 好的
- Me? You want me to get... - Now!
- 我? 你要我... - 下车!
All right, all right. Get out. Hey.
好的好的 下车
All right, I'm... I'm getting out.
好了 我...我在下了
I'm getting out. You see?
在下了 看到没?
Very nifty how you put us down...
能那么放下我们...
without really killing us.
却不让我们受伤 不错
You're good with handcuffs, too, now, huh?
你对手铐也很在行吧?
How you doing?
你们好吗?
You weren't supposed to hear all that.
你不应该知道那些的
- Yeah. - This is real.
- 是啊 - 这都是真的
Now, listen. If I choose to engage with him,
听好 如果我准备和他开战
mum is the word, all right?
"妈妈"就是密语 知道吗?
Sam, I have a record because...
山姆 我那前科是因为...
I wouldn't turn my dad in.
我不肯供出我爸
When have you had to sacrifice...
在你完美的人生里
anything in your perfect little life?
有过不得不作出牺牲的时候吗?
Big guys. Big guys with big guns, huh?
大家伙 拿大炮的大家伙 嗯?
What is Sector Seven? Answer me.
第七区是什么? 回答我
I'm the one who asks questions around here.
这里有权利发问的是我
Not you, young man!
不是你 小伙子!
How'd you know about the aliens?
你怎么知道外星人的事?
Where did you take my parents?
你把我父母带到哪去了?
- I am not at liberty to discuss it. - No?
- 我无权和你们讨论这些 - 是吗?
Hey. You touch me, that's a federal offense.
你碰我的话会触了联邦法
Do-whatever-you-want and-get-away-with-it badge.
为所欲为的徽章 是吗?
Yeah. Brave now all of a sudden,
你现在有这些...
with his big alien friend standing over there.
外星人做靠山就大胆起来了
Where is Sector Seven?
第七区在哪儿?
Wouldn't you like to know?
你们不想知道?
Hey!
喂!
Bumblebee, stop lubricating the man.
大黄蜂 停止润滑他
Get that thing to stop, huh?
别闹了 好不好?
All right, tough guy, take it off.
好了 猛男 开始脱吧
What are you talking about?
什么意思?
- Your clothes, all of it, off. - For what?
- 你的衣服 全脱了 - 为什么?
For threatening my dad.
因为你威胁我爸
Little lady,
小姑娘
this is the beginning of the end of your life.
这是你生命终结的序曲
You're a criminal.
你是个罪犯
Let's face facts. It's in your gene pool.
面对现实吧 上梁不正下梁歪
Those are nice. Now get behind the pole.
不错啊 站到路灯后面
All right.
知道了
This is such a felony, what you're doing.
你们这样做犯了很严重的罪
- I will hunt you down, okay? - He'll hunt you down.
- 我会抓到你的 - 他抓到你的
- Without any remorse! - No remorse.
- 不会心软的 - 不会
- Enjoy. - Okay?
- 呆这吧 - 好了?
We have got to alert everyone.
我们必须通知所有人
They already know. Speaker.
他们已经知道了 扩音器模式
Optimus! Incoming!
擎天柱! 敌人入侵!
Roll out.
出发
Okay, I'm picking up rad readings...
我在那桥下测出...
under that bridge right down there.
有辐射反映
Okay, I'm getting really good rad readings.
辐射反映很强
Forty-two and higher.
超过42个单位
Up you get.
上来
Okay, we're dropping in.
好了 我们要行动了
Really strong readings right down below us.
我们下方辐射指数很高
There he is.
他在那儿
Ship one and two, come on in.
1号和2号船 到这儿来
That's it, right there. Mark him, mark him.
看到了 在那儿 锁定他 锁定他
Okay, there he is. 11:30. Right off the nose.
他在那儿 正前方偏左 正下方
I got it. 12:00.
看到了 正前方
Okay, I'm tracking him. I've got him.
好了 我在跟踪她 找到了
Got him going down the street.
他正沿着街道移动
Okay. Where'd he go, guys? I lost him.
他去哪儿了? 我找不到他
Got no IR signature. Where'd he go?
失去红外信号 他去哪儿了?
Okay, I lost him. I lost him.
信号丢失 信号丢失
Okay, we're coming around.
我们这就赶过去
Easy, you two.
小心点 你们俩
No! No! No, Sam! Sam, don't drop me!
不! 不! 山姆! 山姆! 别放手
Sam, don't! Sam, don't! I'm slipping! I'm slipping!
山姆 不要! 我在往下滑!
- Hold on! - No!
- 抓住! - 不要
Sam!
山姆!
All right, we've got him pinned.
我们找到了他了
We've got him pinned in the river.
目标锁定在河上
I'm in for the shot.
进入射击范围
Stop! Stop!
住手! 住手!
Wait! No!
等等! 不要!
- Take the shot, get him. - Take the shot.
- 射击 抓住他 - 射击
No!
不要!
No! Stop!
不要! 住手!
Stop!
住手!
Get down on the ground! Get down! Get down!
趴在地上! 趴下!
What? Okay.
什么? 好的
Look, he's not fighting back!
看啊 他没有还手
Freeze it! Freeze it! Freeze it!
冻住它! 冻住它!
Stop hurting him!
不要伤害他!
Don't let him move!
让他别动!
I got him here!
我抓住他了
No!
不要!
Happy to see me again?
看到我开不开心?
Put him in a car with his little criminal friend.
把他和他的罪犯朋友关到车子里
I want that thing frozen and ready for transport!
把那东西冷冻起来准备运送
Hang back. Let me check it out.
退后 我去侦查一下
Optimus,
擎天柱
are we just gonna stand here and do nothing?
我们就待在这儿什么都不做?
There's no way to free Bumblebee...
我们没办法为救大黄蜂...
without harming the humans.
而不伤害人类
- But it's not right. He... - Let them leave.
- 但这成何体统 他... - 让他们走吧
The Chinese and the Russians are nearing our
中国和俄国 非常接近我们的...
area of operations in the western Pacific.
西太平洋作战区 这局势...
We feel like this could get out of hand real fast.
我们控制不了多久
But the next couple of hours...
接下来数小时...
may just define his presidency.
就看他们总统怎么做了
US and Chinese task forces approaching...
有中国特遣舰队已经接近...
100 nautical miles of cruise missile range.
巡弋飞弹射程100哩之内
Tell the strike group commander...
告诉航母指挥官
that he's not to engage unless fired on first.
除非对方先进攻 否则不要攻击
- Yes, sir! - Mr. Secretary?
- 是的 长官 - 部长先生?
Tom Banachek. I'm with Sector Seven,
我是汤姆·班奈杰克 隶属第七区
Advanced Research Division.
先进研究部的
Never heard of it.
从没听说过
I'm a little busy, Tom. I think you can see that.
我现在很忙 汤姆 我想你也看得出来
- What's going on here? - I don't know.
- 怎么回事? - 不知道
Sit rep! Talk to me!
情况通报员! 出来说句话!
The whole room's gone down, sir.
整间作业都中断了 先生
I can see that!
我看得出来!
The virus was coded to shut us down.
病毒是用来中断所有作业的
- General? - I'll take a seat.
- 将军? - 我坐在那里等
What do you mean, "shut us down"?
中止作业是什么意思?
They used our network...
它们利用我们网站
to spread out to the whole world.
把病毒散布出去
The blackout's global.
全球性的网络
We have no communications,
我们与全球的卫星
satellite and land lines are dead.
固网联络都中断了
You mean to tell me that I cannot pick up...
你是说我无法...
this telephone and call my family?
用这台电话打给我家?
Mr. Secretary?
部长先生
I'm here under direct order from the President.
我是奉总统之命而来
You really need to see what I have in the case.
你需要看看我这手提箱里的东西
You'll have to accept that there are certain things
你必须知道有些事情
you won't understand right away.
你无法立即了解
Sector Seven is a special-access...
第七区是政府内...
division of the government, convened in...
一个特殊部门 它的成立...
secret under President Hoover 80 years ago.
是80年前奉胡佛总统之密令成立的
You may remember NASA JPL...
您可能记得太空总署和喷推实验室
lost the Beagle 2 Mars Rover.
在火星上损失了猎犬二号机器人
We told them to report the mission...
我们告诉他们将整件任务...
a complete failure. It wasn't.
宣告失败 其实不然
Beagle 2 transmitted 13 seconds.
猎犬二号传输了十三秒钟的影像
This was classified above top secret.
这是比最高机密还要机密的
EDA ended at 170 hours, 48 minutes.
电子活动在170小时48分后停止
More than just a pile of Martian rocks.
火星上不是只有石头
This is the image from Mars.
这是火星上传来的影像
Here's the image your Special Ops team
这是您的特种部队
was able to retrieve from the base attack.
在基地被袭击时拍得的影像
We believe they are of the same exoskeletal type,
我们相信这是相同的外骨骼结构
and obviously not Russian or North Korean.
很显然地并非俄国或北朝鲜能有的
Are we talking about an invasion?
你是说外星入侵?
We intercepted the message...
我们拦劫了...
from your Special Ops team.
特种部队传来的讯息
These things can be hurt...
那些东西知道...
by our weapons and now they know it.
他们也能被我方武器损伤
That's why the virus shut us down,
所以他们用病毒使军事指挥陷入瘫痪
so we can't coordinate against their next attack,
好让我们无法组织防备他们下一波攻击
which I would bet my ridiculous...
我敢用我的政府薪金打赌
government salary is coming soon.
下一波攻击绝对会很快来临
Get word to our fleet commanders...
用国民警卫队的频道...
over the National Guard frequency.
通知舰队指挥官
It's a shortwave radio channel.
那是短波
It might be still working.
可能还有作用
Tell them to turn their ships around and come home.
叫他们调转船头 迅速赶回来
And inform all commands...
通知各司令部
to prepare for imminent attack.
抵抗即将发生的攻击
Captain Lennox,
兰诺斯上尉
we need you and your team to come with us right now!
请带你的部队跟我们来!
Let's go!
我们走!
She's in here.
她在这里
What's going on?
怎么回事?
You're coming with me.
你跟我来
- You're going to be my advisor. - Me, too?
- 你来做我的顾问 - 我也要去?
Who's this?
他是谁?
- He's my advisor. - He comes, too.
- 他是我的顾问 - 那他也来
- So... - What'd they get you for?
- 那么... - 他们要你们来做什么?
I bought a car. Turned out to be an alien robot.
我买了辆车...结果是个外星机器人
Who knew?
谁知道呢
Make a hole! Watch your back!
走直线! 小心你身后!
Please, let this work.
拜托 希望有用
Fire it up, Optimus.
启动吧 擎天柱
The code.
代码
The code on these glasses indicates...
眼镜里的代码显示...
the All Spark is 230 miles from here.
火种源在离这里230哩远处
I sense the Decepticons...
我感觉到霸天虎...
are getting ready to mobilize.
已准备开始行动了
They must know it's here, as well.
他们一定也知道火种源在这里
What about Bumblebee?
大黄蜂怎么办?
We can't just leave him to die...
我们不能就这么失去他...
and become some human experiment!
眼睁睁的被人类当作试验品
He'll die in vain...
如果我们不完成任务的话
if we don't accomplish our mission.
他的牺牲就白费了
Bumblebee is a brave soldier.
大黄峰是名勇敢的战士
This is what he would want.
这会是他所希望的
Why are we fighting to save the humans?
为何我们为拯救人类而战?
They're a primitive and violent race.
他们是个原始且残暴的种族
Were we so different?
我们以前不也是吗?
They're a young species. They have much to learn.
他们是个年轻的种族 还有很多要学
But I've seen goodness in them.
但我看到过他们的优点
Freedom is the right of all sentient beings.
自由是所有有情感的生物之希望
You all know there's only one way to end this war.
你们都知道结束这战争只有一个方法
We must destroy the Cube.
我们必须消灭能量体
If all else fails,
如果其它方法都失败的话
I will unite it with the spark in my chest.
我会将它与我胸中之火光结合
That's suicide.
那是自杀行为
The Cube is raw power. It could destroy you both.
能量体的能源非常不稳定 可能会玉石俱焚
A necessary sacrifice to bring peace to this planet.
为这星球的和平 牺牲是难免的
We cannot let the humans pay for our mistakes.
我们不能让人类为我们的错误而偿命
It's been an honor serving with you all.
很荣幸与你们共战至今
- Autobots, roll out! - We rolling!
- 汽车人 出发! - 出发!
Team attention! Present arms!
立正! 敬礼!
At ease. Captain, Sergeant.
上尉 军士 请稍息
Got your intel. Excellent work.
得到你的情报了 干得好
Thank you, sir. What about the gunships?
谢谢 炮艇机呢?
They're being retrofitted with sabot rounds now.
所有炮艇机上加装了脱壳穿甲弹
If they hit us again, we'll be ready for them.
如果他们再来袭击 没问题的
But it won't do us much good...
但是不恢复全球的通讯
if we can't get world communications back up.
可真是不太妙
Hey, kid.
嘿 小子
I think we got off to a bad start, huh?
我想我们之前有点误会
You must be hungry?
你一定饿了吧?
You want a latte? HoHo? Double venti macchiato?
要不要来杯拿铁咖啡 或者2份超大的玛琪朵咖啡如何?
Where's my car?
我的车呢?
Son, I need you to listen to me very carefully.
小子 你仔细听好
People can die here.
这里人们的生命有危险
We need to know everything you know.
你必须马上告诉我们...
We need to know it now.
你所知道的
Okay.
好吧
But first, I'll take my car, my parents.
但你得先把我的车和我父母还我
Maybe you should write that down.
全部要书面保证
Oh, and her juvie record.
噢 还有她的少年前科
That's got to be gone. Like, forever.
也必须取消 永久地
Come with me. We'll talk about your car.
跟我来 我们谈谈你的车
Thank you.
谢谢
The man's an extortionist.
这家伙简直是勒索
All right, here's the situation.
情况是这样的
You've all had direct contact with the NBEs.
你们都曾直接接触过NBEs
NBEs?
NBEs?
Non-Biological Extraterrestrials.
"非生物类外星人"
Try and keep up with the acronyms.
记清楚了
What you're about to see is totally classified.
你们即将看到的是高度机密
Dear God. What is this?
天啊 这是什么?
We think...
我们认为
when he made his approach over the north pole,
当他飞越北极时
our gravitational field screwed up his telemetry.
地球的地心引力扰乱了他的导航系统
He crashed in the ice,
他坠落到冰里
probably a few thousand years ago.
大概是几千年前的事
We shipped him here to this facility in 1934.
我们在1934年将它运送到这里
We call him NBE One.
我们称它为NBE-1
Well, sir, I don't mean to correct you...
抱歉 先生 我不是想...
on everything you think you know,
故意纠正你的错误
but, I mean, that's Megatron.
但那是威震天
He's the leader of the Decepticons.
他是霸天虎的领袖
He's been in cryostasis since 1935.
它自从1935年就处在冰冻状态
Your great-great-grandfather made one of...
你的曾曾祖父发现了
the greatest discoveries in the history of mankind.
人类史上最大的发现
Fact is, you're looking at...
事实上 你所看到的...
the source of the modern age,
就是现代化的来源
the microchip, lasers, spaceflight,
微晶片 雷射 太空飞行
cars, all reverse-engineered by studying him.
汽车...都是对它进行逆向工程所习得的
NBE One. That's what we call it.
NBE-1 那是我们对它的称呼
And you didn't think the...
你不认为...
United States military might need to know
美国军方需要知道
that you're keeping a hostile...
你把一个外星机器人...
alien robot frozen in the basement?
冰冻在地下室?
Until these events,
在最近发生的事之前
we had no credible threat to national security.
我们并不认为它会对国家安全产生威胁
Well, you got one now.
现在问题可大了
- So why Earth? - It's the All Spark.
- 但为何要来地球? - 因为火种源
All Spark? What is that?
火种源? 那是什么?
Well, yeah, they came here looking for...
他们在找一个...
some sort of cube-Iooking thing.
立方体似的东西
Anyway, Mr. NBE One here, AKA Megatron,
NBE-1 也就是威震天先生
that's what they call him,
他们这样称呼他
who's pretty much the harbinger of death,
他是死亡的使者
wants to use the Cube to transform...
想利用能量体转化
human technology to take over the universe.
人类科技来统治宇宙
That's their plan.
那就是他们的计划
- And you're sure about that? - Yeah.
- 你很确定? - 是的
You guys know where it is, don't you?
你们知道那东西在哪里 是不是?
Follow me.
跟我来
You're about to see our crown jewel.
你们将看到的东西是终极至宝
Carbon dating puts the Cube here around 10,000 BC.
碳-14年代测定预估能量体 是在公元前一万年来到地球的
The first Seven didn't find it until 1913.
七元老在1913年才发现它
They knew it was alien because of...
他们知道这是外星物体 是因为...
the matching hieroglyphics on the Cube
它表面的烙画
as well as NBE One.
和NBE-1表面的烙画非常相似
President Hoover had the dam built around it.
胡佛总统因此建造了水坝将它隐藏于其中
Four football fields thick of concrete
四个足球场厚度的水泥...
A perfect way to hide its energy...
任何人或外面的...
from being detected by anyone...
任何外星种族
or any alien species on the outside.
都无法侦测出它所散发的能量
Wait, back up.
等等
You said the dam hides the Cube's energy.
你说水坝隐藏了他的能量
- What kind exactly? - Good question.
- 哪种能量? - 问得好
Please step inside. They have to lock us in.
请进来 他们要把我们锁在里面
Oh, wow.
喔
What's that?
这是什么?
Freddy Krueger done been up in here or something?
佛瑞迪来过这里吗?
Oh, no, man.
不对
Freddy Krueger have four blades, man.
佛瑞迪有四根爪子
That's only three. That's Wolverine!
那只有三根 那是金刚狼
- Right? That's Wolverine! - That's very funny.
- 对不对? 那是金刚狼 - 很好笑
Anybody have any mechanical devices?
谁有电子产品?
BlackBerry? Key alarm? Cell phone?
黑莓? 车钥匙? 手机?
I got a phone.
我有个手机
Nokias are real nasty.
诺基亚真是酷毙了
You've got to respect the Japanese.
你必须要佩服日本人
They know the way of the samurai.
他们将武士道发挥地淋漓尽至
Nokia's from Finland.
诺基亚是芬兰做的
Yes, but he's, you know, a little strange.
没错 但他 有点奇怪
He's a little strange.
有点奇怪
We're able to take the Cube radiation...
我们把能量体的能源
and funnel it into that box.
传送到这箱子里
Mean little sucker, huh?
好凶的小东西
That thing is freaky!
好可怕!
Kind of like the itty-bitty...
就像劲量的...
Energizer Bunny from hell, huh?
兔宝宝一样
He's breaking the box.
它快把箱子打破了
Go! Go! Go!
行动! 行动!
Move!
出发!
Gentlemen, they know the Cube is here.
各位 他们知道能量体在这里
Banachek. What's going on?
班奈杰克 发生什么事了?
Well, the NBE One hangar has lost power...
NBE-1停机棚断电了
- What? - and the backup generator...
- 什么? - 备用发电机...
is just not gonna cut it.
无法产生足够电量
Do you have an arms room?
你有没有军火库
Megatron! Megatron! Megatron!
威震天! 威震天! 威震天!
I'll bring security to the...
带上保安人员...
Get everyone to the NBE One chamber now!
把所有人派去NBE-1停机棚!
- The lights are out! - Move it! Move it!
- 灯灭了! - 行动!
Let's go!
快!
They're popping our generators!
它们在攻击我们的发电机!
Megatron melting!
威震天冰在融化!
16502. We're losing pressure.
16502 我们在失压
Stand by! Set!
各就各位!
We're losing pressure!
失压...失压
The cryogenic system is failing!
冷冻系统失常
We're losing NBE One!
我们失去NBE-1了
Forty millimeter sabot rounds on that table!
40毫米穿甲弹在那桌上
You got to take me to my car.
你必须带我去我的车
He's gonna know what to do with the Cube.
它知道怎么处理能量体
Your car? It's confiscated.
你的车? 被没收了
Then unconfiscate it.
那就别没收它
We do not know what will happen...
我们不知道让它接近能源体...
if we let it near this thing!
会发生什么事!
You don't know.
是你不知道
Maybe you know, but I don't know.
也许你知道 但我不知道
You just wanna sit here...
你就准备呆在这儿...
and wait and see what happens?
坐以待毙?
I have people's lives at stake here, young man.
很多人的生命掌握在我们手上
Take him to his car!
让他去见他的车!
Drop it.
放下武器
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
喔! 喔! 喔!
Drop your weapon, soldier.
放下你的武器 军人
There's an alien war going on...
外星人已经发动战争了
and you're gonna shoot me?
而你却要杀我?
You know, we didn't ask to be here.
我们没必要杀你
I'm ordering you under S-Seven...
我以第七区的权力...
executive jurisdiction.
命令你放手
S-Seven don't exist.
第七区并不存在
Right. And we don't take orders...
我们不会听命于...
from people that don't exist.
一个不存在的组织
I'm gonna count to five. Okay.
我数到五
Well, I'm gonna count to three.
我数到三
- Simmons? - Yes, sir?
- 西门斯? - 是 先生
I'd do what he says.
我会照他说的做
Losing's really not an option for these guys.
输不是他们这些人的选项
All right. Okay.
好吧 好吧
Hey, you want to lay the fate of the world
你想把世界的命运
on the kid's Camaro? That's cool.
交给这小子的车 那好吧
No, no!
住手! 住手!
Stop! You got to stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
住手! 住手! 住手!
No, no, stop, stop, stop! Let him go! Let him go!
住手! 住手! 住手! 放开他!
Are you okay?
你没事吗?
They didn't hurt you, right?
他们没伤你吧?
Listen to me. The Cube is here...
听我说 能量体在这里
and the Decepticons are coming.
霸天虎已经来了
No, don't worry about them. They're okay. Right?
不 不 别管他们 好吗?
They're not gonna hurt you.
他们不会伤你的
Just back up a little bit. He's friendly. He's fine.
退后一点 他没有恶意
Okay, come on.
好了 来吧
Put the guns down. They're not gonna hurt you.
放下枪 他们不会伤害你的
Here, come with me.
跟我来
I'm gonna take you to the All Spark.
我带你去看火种源
Okay, here we go.
好呀 来了
He doing something. He doing something.
他要做什么了
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
Message from Starfleet, Captain.
来自太空舰队的消息
Let's get to it.
把这个带走 上尉
He's right. We stay here,
他说的对 我们要是留下来
we're screwed with Megatron in the other hangar.
就死定了 威震天就在隔壁的机棚里
Mission City is 22 miles away.
最近的城市在22英哩外
We're gonna sneak that Cube out of here
我们把能量体偷带出去
and we're gonna hide it somewhere in the city.
然后藏在城市里
Good! Right.
很好 就这么做
But we cannot make a stand without the Air Force.
但我们需要空军的帮忙
This place must have some kind of radio link!
这地方一定有无线电装置吧
- Yes. Shortwave, CB. - Right, yes.
- 短波 - 有
Sir, you got to figure out some way...
先生 你一定要想办法
to get word out to them. Let's move!
传递消息出去 我们走
In the alien archive, sir!
是非常旧的仪器
There's an old Army radio console.
之前陆军使用的
- Will it work? - Anything's possible!
- 还能用吗? - 一切皆有可能!
Did you see that...
你看到...
All right, Sam, get it in the car!
山姆 上车!
Mr. Secretary! Get our birds in the air.
部长先生 请继续试着联络空军
When we get to the city, we're gonna find a radio,
等我们到了城市我们再找个无线电
and I'll have Epps vector them in, okay?
让埃普斯无线电导引
Affirmative!
是!
Warning! NBE One cryo-containment failing.
警告 NBE-1冷冻系统故障
Check that backup system!
检查备用系统!
Come on! Get out of here!
快点逃出这里!
Heads up! Look out!
抬头! 小心!
Set a perimeter around the yellow vehicle!
大家帮黄车开一条路
This way, this way, this way!
这边! 这边!
Up there! Let's go!
就在那! 走!
I am Megatron!
我是威震天!
- The Cube's okay? - Yeah, it's fine.
- 能量体没事吧? - 没事
Well, put the seat belt on.
系上安全带
Pour it on him!
弄到他身上!
I live to serve you, Lord Megatron.
很荣幸为您效劳 威震天
Where is the Cube?
能量体呢?
The humans have taken it.
被人类拿走了
You fail me yet again, Starscream. Get them!
你又让我失望了 红蜘蛛 抓住他们
Come on, Mags!
用力!
Over here, sir!
在这边 先生!
Give me a minute. Give me a minute.
等一下 等一下
Come to me, Maxwell, come to me. Plugged in there.
拜托 拜托 插在这
- We're hot! We're live! - Where are the mikes?
- 哈 通了 有电了! - 麦克风在哪?
Mikes?
麦克风!
This doesn't work without mikes, Simmons.
没麦克风也没用
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
不 不 不 不!
Let's find them.
快找找
Kid, get in the chair!
小子 你坐下
Just get in the chair, all right?
你坐下 好吗?
They steal everything out of this place.
他们把什么都偷走了
How do we get the signal out?
我们要怎么传出讯号?
How do we call the Air Force?
我们怎么联络空军?
- Glen? - Huh?
- 格伦? - 嗯?
Can you hotwire this computer...
格伦 你能否把这台电脑...
to transmit a tone through the radio?
接上无线电 然后送出讯号?
What good is that?
那有什么用?
Morse code! You can use this...
你可以把这台电脑连上无线电
to transmit it through that!
然后传送莫尔斯电码!
Okay, I'll do it! Turn it around. Okay, let's see.
好 好! 我可以! 快点 我看看
Simmons, I need a screwdriver!
西门斯 我要个螺丝刀
There's Optimus.
擎天柱来了
Almost done.
快好了
What the hell was that?
那是什么玩意?
Barricade the door!
把门堵住!
- Get something. - Watch out!
- 找些东西 - 小心!
Six, five, four, six, three.
六 五 四 六 三
Here! Put some rounds in!
拿着! 装弹!
Master search.
全局搜索...
I got it! We're transmitting!
我成功了 正在发送
Send exactly what I say!
照我说的写
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
闪开! 快闪开!
Burn, you little sucker! Burn!
烧死你! 你个小杂碎!
"This is Defense Secretary Keller.
这里是国防部长凯勒...
"Get me NORTHCOM commander."
致北方司令部长官
- Whoa! - Whoa!
- 喔! - 喔!
What was that?
刚才是什么啊!
Authenticate emergency action. Blackbird 1195...
启动紧急步骤 黑鸟1195...
Sir, I have an authenticated...
长官 我们确认来自...
ir strike order from Sec Def.
国防部长的空袭命令
- No, no, no, no, no. - What?
- 不 不 不 - 怎么?
It's the same cop!
还是那辆警车!
Block them, block them, block them.
挡住他们!
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
Cool, Mom!
真酷 妈妈!
This is so not good.
情况不妙
He's behind the pillar!
他在柱子后面!
- Shoot that mother... - Maggie, cover fire!
- 打死他 - 玛吉 掩护!
It's the Air Force! They're responding!
空军已经回应
Sucker, burn!
烧死你!
Oh, shit!
哦 糟糕!
Yes! They're sending F-22s to the city!
他们派F-22到城市去了!
Raptors, let's scramble, scramble, scramble.
猛禽 出动! 出动! 出动!
Strike and Dark Star roll call.
攻击机群整队
Come on, let's go! Mount up!
快走! 行动!
Here, I got shortwave radios.
短波无线电
Wait. What am I supposed to do with these?
我怎么用这玩意?
Well, use them! It's all we got!
用它联系 只有这个了!
This is like RadioShack...
这个像是...
dinosaur radios or something, man.
中古电器行的古董了
I'm only gonna get 20 or 30 miles...
范围最多...
out of these things.
20-30英里
Are there any aircraft orbiting the city?
呼叫城市上方的飞机
F-22 at 12:00
12点方向 F-22战斗机
All right, I want planes for air cover...
好的 请求飞机空中掩护
and get Black Hawks on station...
让黑鹰直升机来
to extract that Cube. You got it?
运送能量体
Air Force has arrived! Pop smoke!
空军到了 放烟雾信号
Raptor, Raptor, do you copy?
猛禽猛禽 能否听到
We have you visual.
能看到你们
Green smoke is the mark.
标记是绿色烟雾
Provide air cover...
请提供空中掩护
and vector Black Hawks for extraction.
黑鹰机来接我们
It's Starscream!
是红蜘蛛!
Please tell me you copy.
请回应我
Back up! Take cover! Bumblebee!
退后 掩护 大黄蜂!
No, no, no, no, no! Move!
不 不 不 加把劲!
- Back up! Back up! - Retreat! Fall back!
- 后退 后退! - 快撤!
Incoming!
来了!
Anybody hurt? Everyone okay?
有人受伤吗?
Clear the area!
清场!
Oh, my God.
哦 天啊
Bumblebee? No. Your legs!
大黄蜂 你的腿!
Your legs.
你的腿!
Here. Here, back, back, back, back! You all right?
后退 后退! 你没事吧?
Please get up. Bumblebee? Get up!
拜托 大黄蜂 快起来!
Ratchet!
救护车!
What the hell was that?
刚才怎么回事?
What are you talking about?
你在说什么?
What do you mean, what am I talking about?
什么我什么意思?
They shot at us!
他们向我们开火!
F-22 pilots would never fly below buildings.
F-22不可能飞得比房子还低
That's alien. That ain't friendly!
刚才那个是外星人 不是自己人!
You got to get up. You're okay. You're okay.
你要站起来 你没事的
Come on!
加油!
Army Black Hawk inbound to your location. Over.
直升机接近中 请提供确切方位
Alpha 273 degrees, 10 miles.
A273度 10英里
November Victor, 1.2 clicks north.
N40 往北1.2公里
Move out! Let's go!
快 行动!
Let's go! Move!
快点!
I'm not gonna leave you.
我不会离开你的
Come on, Decepticon punk!
来啊 霸天虎坏蛋!
Oh, my God!
哦 天啊!
Concentrate your fire!
集中火力
Come on. Come on.
快点 快点
Megatron!
威震天!
It's Megatron! Retreat! Move! Fall back!
是威震天 快撤退!
Fall back!
撤退!
Get our guys out of the way! Get out of here! Go!
快让我们的人离开这! 快!
Get them out of the buggy! Move out!
离开这辆车!
We need air cover down here now!
我们需要空中支援 马上要!
Sam, help me with this.
山姆 过来帮我
That all you got, Megatron?
就这点本事 威震天?
Come here, little cretin.
小杂种
You want a piece of me? You want a piece?
你想尝尝厉害么?
No! I want two!
来个双份的!
What's going on?
怎么回事?
Sir! That tank thing's getting back up.
长官 那坦克又起来了
Oh, these things just don't die.
哦 这些家伙怎么不死呢
Oh, we're so dead.
我们惨了
- Wrap it around the head. - Sam!
- 扣在头部! - 山姆!
Where's the Cube?
能量体呢?
- Right there. - Okay.
- 就在这 - 好的
And take that and wrap it around
把它拿过去绕在底盘
the base and then put it around his neck.
然后围在脖子上
- Okay? - Epps, get those Black Hawks here!
- 明白吗? - 埃普斯 让那些黑鹰战机过来!
That building.
那座楼
- Okay. - What?
- 好了 - 什么?
All right, I can't leave my guys back there,
我不能让我的人留在那
so here, take this flare.
你拿着信号弹
Okay, there's a tall, white building...
那边有个白色大楼
with statues on top.
上面有雕塑的
- Go to the roof. Set the flare. - No.
- 到楼顶去 拉开信号弹 - 不
Signal the chopper and set the flare.
打开信号弹通知直升机
No, no. I can't do this!
不 不 我做不到
Listen to me! You're a soldier now!
听着! 你现在是个战士!
All right? I need you to take this Cube.
我要你带走能量体
Get it into military hands while we hold them off,
送回军方手里 这里我们顶着
or a lot of people are gonna die.
否则会死很多人的
You got to go. You got to go.
你快走 你快走
No, I'm not leaving.
不 我不走
- You need to go. Go. - No, I'm not leaving
- 你得走了 - 不 我不走
till I get Bumblebee out of here, okay?
大黄蜂不走 我就不能走
Army Black Hawk requested.
呼叫黑鹰直升机
Immediate evac for civilian boy with precious cargo.
请求立刻送走一个男孩和重要物品
Headed to rooftop marked by flare.
他在房顶上 有信号弹
- Sam, we will protect you. - Okay.
- 山姆 我们会掩护你的 - 好吧
- Epps, where are those planes? - Sam!
- 埃普斯 飞机呢? - 山姆!
No matter what happens,
无论结局会怎样
I'm really glad I got in that car with you.
我都很高兴那天上了你的车
Sam! Get to the building! Move!
山姆! 快行动!
- Decepticons, attack! - Hit it!
- 霸天虎 进攻! - 开火!
Cover fire!
火力掩护!
Watch out!
小心!
Girl, get that tow truck out of here!
快把车开走!
I'm going! I'm going!
马上就走!
Get out of here now!
赶快走!
Megatron!
威震天!
Prime.
擎天柱
Humans don't deserve to live.
人类不配活着
They deserve to choose for themselves.
这要由人类自己决定
Then you will die with them!
跟他们一起去死吧!
Join them in extinction!
一同毁灭!
Keep moving, Sam!
继续跑 山姆!
Don't stop!
别停!
No!
不!
Sam, get to the building!
山姆 快去大楼!
Give me that Cube, boy!
把能量体给我 孩子!
Did that jerk just dent my car?
那个臭小子不会把我车撞瘪了吧?
You're not gonna get me. You're not gonna get me!
你抓不到我的 你抓不到我的!
I smell you, boy!
我闻到你的气味了 臭小子!
Maggot!
小杂种!
Oh, no!
哦 不!
I'll drive! You shoot!
我开车 你开枪!
This isn't going well!
情况不妙
Shoot! Shoot!
开枪 开枪
Nice shot.
打得好
That tank is definitely dead now.
那坦克这次肯定死了
All right, let's go! We got business!
大家继续战斗
Hey!
嘿!
Hey! I'm over here!
嘿! 我在这!
We've got the boy.
找到男孩了
Watch out!
小心!
Missile!
导弹!
Hang on, Sam!
撑住 山姆!
No! No!
不! 不!
Is it fear or courage that compels you, fleshling?
这到底是恐惧还是勇气控制着你?
Where do I go?
该怎么办?
Give me the All Spark and you may live to be my pet.
把火种源给我 我饶你不死 当我的宠物
Oh, no, no, no, no.
不 不 不 不
I'm never giving you this All Spark!
我绝对不会给你这个火种源!
Oh, so unwise.
真愚钝
I got you, boy.
接住了
Hold on to the Cube!
抱紧能量体!
- Oh, no. Oh, no! - Disgusting.
- 哦 不! - 真恶心
Sam?
山姆
You risked your life to protect the Cube.
你用你的生命保护了能量体
No sacrifice,
没有付出
- no victory. - If I cannot defeat Megatron,
- 就没有胜利 - 如果杀不了威震天
you must push the Cube into my chest.
你一定要把能量体塞入我的胸膛
I will sacrifice myself to destroy it.
我会牺牲自己 与它同归于尽
Get behind me.
躲到我身后去
It's you and me, Megatron.
只有你我两个的决斗了 威震天
No, it's just me, Prime.
不 只有我 擎天柱
At the end of this day,
决战结束时
one shall stand, one shall fall.
胜者会屹立 败者会倒下
You still fight for the weak! That is why you lose!
你仍然在为弱者而战 所以你必输无疑
Fighter jets in 60 seconds.
战机60秒后到
We got friendlies mixed with bad guys.
两派机器人都有
Targets will be marked.
我们会用激光标记敌人
Hey!
嘿!
Bring the rain. All right?
呼叫空袭 明白?
All right, let's kill these things.
我们来消灭这些东西
- Move, move, move! - Remember, aim low.
- 快走! - 记住 向下瞄准
Armor's weak under the chest.
盔甲的弱点在胸部下面
Target marked. Still waiting.
目标已被标出 等待中
Time on target, 20 seconds.
20秒钟到达目标
F-22s, we're still waiting.
F-22战机 我们还在等
Move out!
快走!
Incoming!
来了!
Weapons armed. Status green.
载弹发射 目标绿色
Run! Move!
快走!
Second wave's on approach.
第二波来了
What is that? Break off!
那是谁 小心!
Two, get a lock! Pop that guy!
2号 锁定 干掉他!
Stay on him. Keep him in your sights.
盯住他 别让他跑了
Take him out!
把他带走!
Two's down!
2号中弹!
I'll kill you!
我要杀了你!
Mine! All Spark!
火种源是我的!
Sam! Put the Cube in my chest! Now!
山姆! 快把能量体塞入我的胸膛!
Sam!
山姆!
No, Sam!
不 山姆!
Hold up.
不要开火
You left me no choice, brother.
你逼得我别无选择 兄弟
Sam, I owe you my life.
山姆 我欠你一条命
We are in your debt.
我们都欠你的情
Prime, we couldn't save him.
擎天柱 我们没能救他
Jazz.
爵士
We lost a great comrade,
我们失去了一位杰出的战友
but gained new ones.
但也结识了新的战友
Thank you, all of you.
谢谢大家
You honor us with your bravery.
我们敬佩你们的勇敢
Permission to speak, sir?
我有话要说 长官
Permission granted, old friend.
请讲吧 老朋友
You speak now?
你能说话了?
I wish to stay with the boy.
我希望和男孩呆在一起
If that is his choice.
如果他也同意
Yes.
同意
Gentlemen, the President has ordered...
总统已经下令...
Sector Seven be terminated...
将第七区组织解散
and the remains of the dead aliens disposed of.
处理掉外星人尸体
The Laurentian Abyss is seven miles below sea level,
罗伦提恩海沟有7英里深
deepest place on our planet.
地球上最深的地方
The massive depth and pressure there,
这个深度的...
coupled with subfreezing temperatures,
极高压与极低温
would crush and entomb them,
会把尸体压扁
leaving no evidence.
不留任何蛛丝马迹
With the All Spark gone,
火种源被摧毁
we cannot return life to our planet.
我们已经无法回到自己的星球
And fate has yielded its reward,
造化弄人
a new world to call home.
我们现在有了一个新家叫做地球
We live among its people now, hiding in plain sight,
我们已经和这里的人民共同生活 藏在他们眼皮之下
but watching over them in secret,
也在悄悄地地保护他们
waiting, protecting.
等待 保护
I have witnessed their capacity for courage.
我目睹了他们的勇气
And though we are worlds apart,
尽管和我们来自不同世界
like us, there's more to them than meets the eye.
但像我们一样 他们也不可貌相
I am Optimus Prime...
我是擎天柱
and I send this message to any surviving Autobots
在这里召唤所有
taking refuge among the stars.
在宇宙中流亡的汽车人
We are here.
我们在这里
We are waiting.
我们在等待
Can you shed any light on the recent,
你们知道最近这个地方有
so-called alien activity in the area?
所谓的外星人活动吗?
Do you know what? I think that...
你知道吗? 我想...
if there was some sort of an alien
如果真有外星人...
- infestation... - Yeah
- 入侵... - 嗯
They, the government,
我们的政府
would be the first to let you know.
会第一个让我们知道
The government would let us know.
政府会让我们知道的
- I mean, this is America. - Yeah.
- 我是说 这里是美国 - 对
You know, that's how we know we live in a free land,
正因为那样 我们才知道 我们生活在一片自由的土地上
because there's no secrets.
因为没有秘密
They'd say, "Hey! Duck and cover."
他们会说"嘿 快找掩护"
Your head is kind of...
你的头和电视里面...
of a different size than it is on television.
有点不一样大